{
	"description": "Kanji for 日本漢字能力検定 3級",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "満悦", "answers": [ "まんえつ" ], "comment": "great delight; rapture" },
	{ "question": "一掃", "answers": [ "いっそう" ], "comment": "clean sweep; purging; doing away with; eradication" },
	{ "question": "一斤", "answers": [ "いっきん" ], "comment": "1 kin (~0.6kg)\n1 loaf of bread" },
	{ "question": "一貫", "answers": [ "いっかん" ], "comment": "consistency; coherence; integration\none kan (approx. 3.75 kg, 8.3 lb)\none piece of sushi" },
	{ "question": "一騎打ち", "answers": [ "いっきうち" ], "comment": "personal combat; one-to-one fight" },
	{ "question": "下請け", "answers": [ "したうけ" ], "comment": "subcontract\nsubcontractor (person or company)" },
	{ "question": "不吉", "answers": [ "ふきつ" ], "comment": "ominous; sinister; unlucky; inauspicious" },
	{ "question": "不審", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "incomplete understanding; doubt; question; distrust; suspicion; strangeness; infidelity" },
	{ "question": "不穏", "answers": [ "ふおん" ], "comment": "disquieting; threatening; turbulent; restless; unsettled; disturbing" },
	{ "question": "丘陵", "answers": [ "きゅうりょう" ], "comment": "hill" },
	{ "question": "並べる", "answers": [ "ならべる" ], "comment": "to line up; to set up; to arrange in a line\nto enumerate; to itemize\nto be equal (to); to compare well (with); to be as good (as)" },
	{ "question": "中堅", "answers": [ "ちゅうけん" ], "comment": "main body (of troops)\nnucleus; backbone; mainstay; key figure\ncenter field; centre field; center fielder; centre fielder\nathlete competing in the middle-number match in a team competition, i.e. second in 3-on-3, third in 5-on-5 (kendo, judo, etc.)\nmedium-level; mid-level; midsize" },
	{ "question": "主催", "answers": [ "しゅさい" ], "comment": "sponsorship (i.e. conducting under one's auspices); promotion; organizing; organising; hosting; staging" },
	{ "question": "主軸", "answers": [ "しゅじく" ], "comment": "main spindle; main shaft\nlinchpin; pivot\nprincipal axis; main axis" },
	{ "question": "乏しい", "answers": [ "とぼしい" ], "comment": "meagre; meager; scarce; limited; destitute; hard up; lacking; scanty; poor" },
	{ "question": "乱れる", "answers": [ "みだれる" ], "comment": "to be disordered; to be disarranged; to be disarrayed; to be disheveled; to be dishevelled\nto be discomposed; to be upset; to get confused; to be disturbed\nto lapse into chaos (due to war, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "了承", "answers": [ "りょうしょう" ], "comment": "acknowledgement; acknowledgment; understanding (e.g. \"please be understanding of the mess during our renovation\"); noting; acceptance" },
	{ "question": "争う", "answers": [ "あらそう" ], "comment": "to compete; to contest; to contend\nto quarrel; to argue; to dispute; to be at variance; to oppose\n(usu. in negative form) to deny (e.g. evidence)\nto go against; to fight against; to oppose; to resist; to deny" },
	{ "question": "争奪", "answers": [ "そうだつ" ], "comment": "struggle; contest" },
	{ "question": "互譲", "answers": [ "ごじょう" ], "comment": "conciliation; compromise" },
	{ "question": "交換", "answers": [ "こうかん" ], "comment": "exchange; interchange; switching; reciprocity; barter; substitution; replacement; clearing (of checks, cheques)" },
	{ "question": "交錯", "answers": [ "こうさく" ], "comment": "mixture; blending; complication; crossing; intersecting; interlacing" },
	{ "question": "令嬢", "answers": [ "れいじょう" ], "comment": "(your) daughter; young woman" },
	{ "question": "企てる", "answers": [ "くわだてる" ], "comment": "to plan; to plot; to propose; to design; to intend; to contemplate\nto attempt (e.g. suicide, murder); to undertake (e.g. business)\nto stand on tip-toes" },
	{ "question": "企画", "answers": [ "きかく" ], "comment": "planning; project; plan; design" },
	{ "question": "伏せる", "answers": [ "ふせる" ], "comment": "to lie down; to retire; to go to bed (with an illness)\nto lay something upside down; to turn something over; to lay something face down\nto cover; to lay (pipes); to lay (an ambush); to hide; to conceal" },
	{ "question": "伏兵", "answers": [ "ふくへい" ], "comment": "ambush; troops in ambush" },
	{ "question": "伏線", "answers": [ "ふくせん" ], "comment": "foreshadowing\npreparation; precautionary measures" },
	{ "question": "伐採", "answers": [ "ばっさい" ], "comment": "lumbering; felling; deforestation" },
	{ "question": "伴う", "answers": [ "ともなう" ], "comment": "to accompany; to go hand in hand with; to be consequent upon\nto be accompanied by; to bring with; to take with; to be involved in" },
	{ "question": "伸張", "answers": [ "しんちょう" ], "comment": "expansion; extension; elongation; stretching; uncompression" },
	{ "question": "似る", "answers": [ "にる" ], "comment": "to resemble; to look like; to take after\nto be similar (in status, condition, etc.); to be close; to be alike; to be like" },
	{ "question": "佳作", "answers": [ "かさく" ], "comment": "good piece of work\nhonourable mention (honorable)" },
	{ "question": "佳境", "answers": [ "かきょう" ], "comment": "climax (story); best part; most interesting part" },
	{ "question": "例える", "answers": [ "たとえる" ], "comment": "to compare; to liken; to speak figuratively; to illustrate; to use a simile" },
	{ "question": "侍", "answers": [ "さむらい" ], "comment": "warrior (esp. of military retainers of daimyos in the Edo period); samurai\nman in attendance (on a person of high standing); retainer" },
	{ "question": "侍従", "answers": [ "じじゅう" ], "comment": "chamberlain" },
	{ "question": "便乗", "answers": [ "びんじょう" ], "comment": "taking advantage of a ride or an opportunity; taking a ship" },
	{ "question": "促す", "answers": [ "うながす" ], "comment": "to urge; to press; to prompt; to suggest; to demand; to stimulate; to quicken; to incite; to invite (attention to)" },
	{ "question": "促進", "answers": [ "そくしん" ], "comment": "promotion; acceleration; encouragement; facilitation; spurring on" },
	{ "question": "保留", "answers": [ "ほりゅう" ], "comment": "reserve; putting on hold; deferment\nhold (e.g. telephone button); pending" },
	{ "question": "修繕", "answers": [ "しゅうぜん" ], "comment": "repair; mending" },
	{ "question": "俳句", "answers": [ "はいく" ], "comment": "haiku; 17-mora poem, usu. in 3 lines of 5, 7 and 5 morae" },
	{ "question": "倹約", "answers": [ "けんやく" ], "comment": "thrift; economy; frugality" },
	{ "question": "停滞", "answers": [ "ていたい" ], "comment": "stagnation; tie-up; congestion; retention; accumulation; falling into arrears" },
	{ "question": "偶像", "answers": [ "ぐうぞう" ], "comment": "image; idol; statue" },
	{ "question": "偶然", "answers": [ "ぐうぜん" ], "comment": "coincidence; chance; accident; fortuity\nby chance; unexpectedly\ncontingency (philosophy)" },
	{ "question": "催す", "answers": [ "もよおす" ], "comment": "to hold (a meeting); to give (a dinner); to show signs of\nto feel (sensation, emotion, call of nature, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "催促", "answers": [ "さいそく" ], "comment": "pressing; demanding; urging; demand; request; claim" },
	{ "question": "債権", "answers": [ "さいけん" ], "comment": "credit; claim" },
	{ "question": "傷める", "answers": [ "いためる" ], "comment": "to hurt; to injure; to cause pain\nto harm; to damage; to spoil\nto worry; to bother; to be grieved over; to afflict\nto cause financial loss; to hurt one's pocket" },
	{ "question": "傾聴", "answers": [ "けいちょう" ], "comment": "listening closely" },
	{ "question": "働く", "answers": [ "はたらく" ], "comment": "to work; to labor; to labour\nto function; to operate; to be effective; to work (i.e. ... works); to come into play\nto commit (e.g. a crime); to perpetrate; to do; to act; to practise; to practice\nto be conjugated" },
	{ "question": "優しい", "answers": [ "やさしい" ], "comment": "tender; kind; gentle; graceful; affectionate; amiable" },
	{ "question": "優れた", "answers": [ "すぐれた" ], "comment": "great; excellent; outstanding" },
	{ "question": "優先", "answers": [ "ゆうせん" ], "comment": "preference; priority; precedence" },
	{ "question": "克明", "answers": [ "こくめい" ], "comment": "detailed; elaborate; faithful (copy); accurate\nscrupulous; diligent; conscientious" },
	{ "question": "克服", "answers": [ "こくふく" ], "comment": "conquest (of a difficulty, illness, handicap, etc.); overcoming; bringing under control; subjugation; victory over" },
	{ "question": "免れる", "answers": [ "まぬがれる", "まぬかれる" ], "comment": "to escape (disaster, death, etc.); to be saved from; to be rescued from\nto avoid (e.g. punishment); to evade (e.g. responsibility); to avert; to elude; to be exempted from" },
	{ "question": "免税", "answers": [ "めんぜい" ], "comment": "tax exemption; duty exemption" },
	{ "question": "免除", "answers": [ "めんじょ" ], "comment": "exemption; exoneration; discharge" },
	{ "question": "全く", "answers": [ "まったく" ], "comment": "really; truly; entirely; completely; wholly; perfectly\nindeed\ngood grief (expression of exasperation)" },
	{ "question": "共謀", "answers": [ "きょうぼう" ], "comment": "conspiracy; collusion; complicity; being in cahoots" },
	{ "question": "典型的", "answers": [ "てんけいてき" ], "comment": "typical; prototypical; representative; stereotypical; model; ideal; archetypal; quintessential" },
	{ "question": "内紛", "answers": [ "ないふん" ], "comment": "domestic discord; internal discord; internal strife; internal struggle; infighting" },
	{ "question": "円滑", "answers": [ "えんかつ" ], "comment": "smooth; undisturbed; uninterrupted; harmonious" },
	{ "question": "冗漫", "answers": [ "じょうまん" ], "comment": "verbosity" },
	{ "question": "冗談", "answers": [ "じょうだん" ], "comment": "jest; joke; funny story" },
	{ "question": "冷凍", "answers": [ "れいとう" ], "comment": "freezing; cold storage; refrigeration" },
	{ "question": "凍える", "answers": [ "こごえる" ], "comment": "to freeze (of one's body); to be frozen; to become numb (with cold); to be chilled" },
	{ "question": "凍結", "answers": [ "とうけつ" ], "comment": "freeze (e.g. program, food)" },
	{ "question": "凝らす", "answers": [ "こらす" ], "comment": "to freeze; to congeal\nto concentrate one's attention on; to devote oneself to something; to ponder; to meditate\nto concentrate; to devote; to apply; to strain; to rack" },
	{ "question": "凝縮", "answers": [ "ぎょうしゅく" ], "comment": "condensation (of ideas, emotions, etc.)\ncondensation (of a vapour or gas)" },
	{ "question": "凝視", "answers": [ "ぎょうし" ], "comment": "stare; gaze; fixation" },
	{ "question": "処遇", "answers": [ "しょぐう" ], "comment": "treatment (of a person); dealing with" },
	{ "question": "出帆", "answers": [ "しゅっぱん" ], "comment": "sailing; departure" },
	{ "question": "分泌", "answers": [ "ぶんぴつ" ], "comment": "secretion" },
	{ "question": "切符", "answers": [ "きっぷ" ], "comment": "ticket" },
	{ "question": "刑期", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "prison term" },
	{ "question": "削る", "answers": [ "けずる" ], "comment": "to shave (wood or leather); to sharpen; to plane; to whittle; to pare; to scrape off\nto shave off (e.g. a budget, expenses, a salary, etc.); to curtail; to cut down\nto cross out; to reduce; to curtail; to remove; to erase; to delete\nto shave off (esp. concrete)\nto take a percentage; to take a cut" },
	{ "question": "割れる", "answers": [ "われる" ], "comment": "to break; to be smashed\nto split; to crack; to fissure; to be torn\nto be divided; to cleave\nto come to light; to be identified; to be established; to become clear" },
	{ "question": "割引", "answers": [ "わりびき" ], "comment": "discount; reduction; rebate; (after a number) tenths discounted; tenths reduced" },
	{ "question": "創業", "answers": [ "そうぎょう" ], "comment": "establishment (of a business, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "励ます", "answers": [ "はげます" ], "comment": "to encourage; to cheer; to raise (the voice)" },
	{ "question": "効率", "answers": [ "こうりつ" ], "comment": "efficiency; efficacy; performance; utility factor" },
	{ "question": "勇敢", "answers": [ "ゆうかん" ], "comment": "brave; heroic; gallant" },
	{ "question": "動揺", "answers": [ "どうよう" ], "comment": "shaking; trembling; pitching; rolling; oscillation\ndisturbance; unrest; agitation; excitement; commotion; turmoil; discomposure; feeling shaken" },
	{ "question": "勘", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "perception; intuition; the sixth sense" },
	{ "question": "勘違い", "answers": [ "かんちがい" ], "comment": "misunderstanding; wrong guess" },
	{ "question": "務める", "answers": [ "つとめる" ], "comment": "to work (for); to be employed (at); to serve (in)\nto serve (as); to act (as); to fill (the position of); to play the role (of)\nto conduct a religious service" },
	{ "question": "募る", "answers": [ "つのる" ], "comment": "to grow violent; to become stronger; to become worse\nto invite contributions, etc.; to solicit help, participation, etc.; to recruit (e.g. soldiers)" },
	{ "question": "募集", "answers": [ "ぼしゅう" ], "comment": "recruiting; selection; taking applications\nraising; collection; subscription; soliciting (e.g. donations)\nflotation (shares, loans, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "勢い", "answers": [ "いきおい" ], "comment": "force; vigor; vigour; energy; spirit; life\ninfluence; authority; power; might\nimpetus; momentum; course (of events)\nnaturally; necessarily" },
	{ "question": "勤倹", "answers": [ "きんけん" ], "comment": "industry; diligence; frugality" },
	{ "question": "北斗", "answers": [ "ほくと" ], "comment": "the Big Dipper (asterism); the Plough; the Plow" },
	{ "question": "匿名", "answers": [ "とくめい" ], "comment": "anonymity; using an assumed name" },
	{ "question": "卑しい", "answers": [ "いやしい" ], "comment": "lowborn; humble; lowly\nvulgar; coarse; crude; mean; base; vile\nshabby\ngreedy; gluttonous; avaricious" },
	{ "question": "卑劣", "answers": [ "ひれつ" ], "comment": "mean; foul play; cowardly; base" },
	{ "question": "卑屈", "answers": [ "ひくつ" ], "comment": "menial; meanness; servility; abject" },
	{ "question": "卓抜", "answers": [ "たくばつ" ], "comment": "excellence; superiority; preeminence; prevalence" },
	{ "question": "卓越", "answers": [ "たくえつ" ], "comment": "preeminence; excellence; superiority; transcendence" },
	{ "question": "危うい", "answers": [ "あやうい" ], "comment": "dangerous; risky; hazardous; perilous; precarious\nin danger; in jeopardy; critical; grave; at risk\nuncertain; unreliable; insecure; unsteady; doubtful\nclose (i.e. a close call); narrow" },
	{ "question": "危篤", "answers": [ "きとく" ], "comment": "critical condition; being on the verge of death" },
	{ "question": "卸す", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "to sell wholesale\nto grate (e.g. vegetables)\nto cut up fish" },
	{ "question": "卸値", "answers": [ "おろしね" ], "comment": "wholesale price" },
	{ "question": "厘", "answers": [ "りん" ], "comment": "one-hundredth; 0.3 mm (one-hundredth of a sun); 0.1 percent (one-hundredth of a wari); 0.0375 grams (one-hundredth of a monme)\nold monetary unit (0.001 yen)" },
	{ "question": "厘毛", "answers": [ "りんもう" ], "comment": "farthing; trifle" },
	{ "question": "原子炉", "answers": [ "げんしろ" ], "comment": "atomic reactor; nuclear reactor" },
	{ "question": "厳しい", "answers": [ "きびしい" ], "comment": "severe; strict; rigid; unsparing; relentless\nintense (e.g. cold); harsh; tough" },
	{ "question": "厳格", "answers": [ "げんかく" ], "comment": "severe; rigid; stern; strictness; rigor; rigour; austerity" },
	{ "question": "参謀", "answers": [ "さんぼう" ], "comment": "staff officer; military staff\nadviser; counselor; counsellor" },
	{ "question": "又", "answers": [ "また" ], "comment": "again; and; also; still (doing something)" },
	{ "question": "又聞き", "answers": [ "またぎき" ], "comment": "hearsay; learning by hearsay" },
	{ "question": "双子", "answers": [ "ふたご" ], "comment": "twins; twin" },
	{ "question": "双方", "answers": [ "そうほう" ], "comment": "two way; both parties; mutual; both" },
	{ "question": "双眼鏡", "answers": [ "そうがんきょう" ], "comment": "binoculars; field glasses" },
	{ "question": "収監", "answers": [ "しゅうかん" ], "comment": "imprisonment" },
	{ "question": "収穫", "answers": [ "しゅうかく" ], "comment": "harvest; crop; ingathering\nfruits (of one's labors); results" },
	{ "question": "口内炎", "answers": [ "こうないえん" ], "comment": "mouth ulcer; stomatitis" },
	{ "question": "古墳", "answers": [ "こふん" ], "comment": "ancient burial mound; barrow; tumulus" },
	{ "question": "吉報", "answers": [ "きっぽう" ], "comment": "good news" },
	{ "question": "同伴", "answers": [ "どうはん" ], "comment": "to accompany; to go with\ncompany; companion" },
	{ "question": "同胞", "answers": [ "どうほう" ], "comment": "brethren; brothers; fellow countrymen; fellowman; compatriot" },
	{ "question": "名匠", "answers": [ "めいしょう" ], "comment": "master craftsman; skillful worker" },
	{ "question": "名簿", "answers": [ "めいぼ" ], "comment": "register of names; list of names; roll; register\nproof of identity (for nobles, doctors, etc.) (Heian period)" },
	{ "question": "周知", "answers": [ "しゅうち" ], "comment": "common knowledge; being well-known; making (something) well-known" },
	{ "question": "哀れ", "answers": [ "あわれ" ], "comment": "pity; sorrow; grief; misery; compassion; pathos\npitiable; pitiful; pathetic; miserable\nalack; alas" },
	{ "question": "哀切", "answers": [ "あいせつ" ], "comment": "pathetic; plaintive" },
	{ "question": "哲学", "answers": [ "てつがく" ], "comment": "philosophy" },
	{ "question": "唱える", "answers": [ "となえる" ], "comment": "to recite; to chant\nto cry; to yell; to shout\nto advocate; to advance; to preach; to insist" },
	{ "question": "商魂", "answers": [ "しょうこん" ], "comment": "commercial spirit" },
	{ "question": "喚問", "answers": [ "かんもん" ], "comment": "summons" },
	{ "question": "喚起", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "arousal; excitation; awakening; evocation" },
	{ "question": "喜ぶ", "answers": [ "よろこぶ" ], "comment": "to be delighted; to be glad; to be pleased\nto congratulate\nto gratefully accept" },
	{ "question": "喫煙", "answers": [ "きつえん" ], "comment": "smoking" },
	{ "question": "営む", "answers": [ "いとなむ" ], "comment": "to run (a business); to operate; to conduct; to practice (law, medicine, etc.)\nto carry out; to perform; to lead (a life)\nto hold (a Buddhist or Shinto ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "嘱託", "answers": [ "しょくたく" ], "comment": "commission; charge (person with); entrusting with\npart-time (employee)" },
	{ "question": "因縁", "answers": [ "いんねん" ], "comment": "fate; destiny\nconnection; tie; bond; origin\npretext; justification\nhetu and prataya (direct causes and indirect conditions, which underlie the actions of all things)" },
	{ "question": "団塊", "answers": [ "だんかい" ], "comment": "mass; lump\nbaby boom generation (of 1947-1949); babyboomer (born between 1947-1949)" },
	{ "question": "地獄", "answers": [ "じごく" ], "comment": "hell" },
	{ "question": "坑道", "answers": [ "こうどう" ], "comment": "tunnel; (mine) level" },
	{ "question": "埋没", "answers": [ "まいぼつ" ], "comment": "burying; embedding; implantation" },
	{ "question": "埋葬", "answers": [ "まいそう" ], "comment": "burial" },
	{ "question": "執念", "answers": [ "しゅうねん" ], "comment": "tenacity; persistence; obsession; implacability" },
	{ "question": "基礎", "answers": [ "きそ" ], "comment": "foundation; basis" },
	{ "question": "基軸", "answers": [ "きじく" ], "comment": "key; yardstick; criterion; standard" },
	{ "question": "報われる", "answers": [ "むくわれる" ], "comment": "to be repaid; to be rewarded" },
	{ "question": "塊", "answers": [ "かたまり" ], "comment": "lump; mass; bundle; clump; clod; cluster\ngroup; crowd\nembodiment (of an idea, quality, feeling etc.); personification" },
	{ "question": "塗料", "answers": [ "とりょう" ], "comment": "paints; painting material" },
	{ "question": "塗装", "answers": [ "とそう" ], "comment": "coating; painting" },
	{ "question": "墜落", "answers": [ "ついらく" ], "comment": "falling; crashing" },
	{ "question": "墨", "answers": [ "すみ" ], "comment": "sumi; India ink; Chinese ink; ink stick; ink-cake\nsquid ink; octopus ink\ncarpenter's inking string\nMexico" },
	{ "question": "墨守", "answers": [ "ぼくしゅ" ], "comment": "adherence (to custom, tradition)" },
	{ "question": "墳墓", "answers": [ "ふんぼ" ], "comment": "grave; tomb" },
	{ "question": "墾田", "answers": [ "こんでん" ], "comment": "new rice field" },
	{ "question": "壇上", "answers": [ "だんじょう" ], "comment": "on a stage; on a platform; on an altar" },
	{ "question": "変哲", "answers": [ "へんてつ" ], "comment": "unusual" },
	{ "question": "外郭", "answers": [ "がいかく" ], "comment": "outer wall (e.g. castle); outer block (enclosure)\noutline; contour" },
	{ "question": "多岐", "answers": [ "たき" ], "comment": "digression; many divergences" },
	{ "question": "多湿", "answers": [ "たしつ" ], "comment": "high humidity" },
	{ "question": "大綱", "answers": [ "たいこう" ], "comment": "fundamental principles; outline; general features\nthick rope\nfundamental principles; outline; general features" },
	{ "question": "大胆", "answers": [ "だいたん" ], "comment": "bold; daring; audacious" },
	{ "question": "天然痘", "answers": [ "てんねんとう" ], "comment": "smallpox; variola" },
	{ "question": "失墜", "answers": [ "しっつい" ], "comment": "abasement; fall; forfeiture; sinking (in people's estimation)" },
	{ "question": "奉仕", "answers": [ "ほうし" ], "comment": "service; ministry; attendance; church work\noffering goods at a reduced price; providing a service for free" },
	{ "question": "奉納", "answers": [ "ほうのう" ], "comment": "dedication; offering; presentation; oblation" },
	{ "question": "契機", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "opportunity; chance" },
	{ "question": "契約", "answers": [ "けいやく" ], "comment": "contract; compact; agreement" },
	{ "question": "奪う", "answers": [ "うばう" ], "comment": "to snatch away; to dispossess; to steal" },
	{ "question": "奮う", "answers": [ "ふるう" ], "comment": "to muster (e.g. one's courage); to call forth; to rouse up; to be enlivened; to be invigorated" },
	{ "question": "妨げ", "answers": [ "さまたげ" ], "comment": "obstruction; hindrance" },
	{ "question": "妨げる", "answers": [ "さまたげる" ], "comment": "to disturb; to prevent; to obstruct; to hinder" },
	{ "question": "妨害", "answers": [ "ぼうがい" ], "comment": "disturbance; obstruction; hindrance; jamming; interference" },
	{ "question": "委嘱", "answers": [ "いしょく" ], "comment": "entrusting (with)" },
	{ "question": "委託", "answers": [ "いたく" ], "comment": "entrusting (something to a person); consignment (of goods); putting in someone's charge; trust; commission" },
	{ "question": "姫君", "answers": [ "ひめぎみ" ], "comment": "daughter of a person of high rank (i.e. a king, noble, aristocrat, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "姿", "answers": [ "すがた" ], "comment": "figure; form; shape\nappearance; dress; guise\nstate; condition; picture; image\nform (of a waka)\ndressed in ...; wearing ..." },
	{ "question": "娯楽", "answers": [ "ごらく" ], "comment": "pleasure; amusement" },
	{ "question": "婿", "answers": [ "むこ" ], "comment": "husband; groom\n(one's) son-in-law" },
	{ "question": "嫁ぐ", "answers": [ "とつぐ" ], "comment": "to marry (of a woman); to become a bride; to marry into (a family)\nto have sexual intercourse (archaism)" },
	{ "question": "嬢", "answers": [ "じょう" ], "comment": "unmarried woman\nMiss\n-ess; -ette" },
	{ "question": "子豚", "answers": [ "こぶた" ], "comment": "piglet" },
	{ "question": "孤島", "answers": [ "ことう" ], "comment": "solitary island" },
	{ "question": "孤立", "answers": [ "こりつ" ], "comment": "isolation; being alone; being friendless" },
	{ "question": "宇宙", "answers": [ "うちゅう" ], "comment": "universe; cosmos; space" },
	{ "question": "完了", "answers": [ "かんりょう" ], "comment": "completion; conclusion\nperfect (tense, form, aspect)\nend; completion" },
	{ "question": "完封", "answers": [ "かんぷう" ], "comment": "complete blockade (seal); baseball shutout" },
	{ "question": "官吏", "answers": [ "かんり" ], "comment": "government official; clerk" },
	{ "question": "実施", "answers": [ "じっし" ], "comment": "enforcement; implementation; putting into practice; carrying out; operation; working (e.g. working parameters); enactment" },
	{ "question": "宴席", "answers": [ "えんせき" ], "comment": "banquet; dinner party" },
	{ "question": "家畜", "answers": [ "かちく" ], "comment": "domestic animals; livestock; cattle" },
	{ "question": "容赦", "answers": [ "ようしゃ" ], "comment": "pardon; forgiveness; mercy\nleniency; going easy (on someone)" },
	{ "question": "密封", "answers": [ "みっぷう" ], "comment": "hermetically seal; sealing (e.g. envelope)" },
	{ "question": "寝癖", "answers": [ "ねぐせ" ], "comment": "bed hair; hair disarranged during sleep\nhabit of moving around in one's sleep; sleeping habit" },
	{ "question": "審判", "answers": [ "しんぱん" ], "comment": "refereeing; trial; judgement; judgment; umpire; referee" },
	{ "question": "審議", "answers": [ "しんぎ" ], "comment": "deliberation" },
	{ "question": "寿", "answers": [ "ことぶき" ], "comment": "congratulations; felicitations; best wishes\nlongevity; long life" },
	{ "question": "封印", "answers": [ "ふういん" ], "comment": "seal; stamp\nto stamp; to affix a seal; to seal up; to seal off" },
	{ "question": "封鎖", "answers": [ "ふうさ" ], "comment": "blockade\nfreezing (funds)" },
	{ "question": "専ら", "answers": [ "もっぱら" ], "comment": "wholly; solely; entirely; exclusively; devotedly; fixedly\nprincipally; mostly; chiefly; mainly" },
	{ "question": "将棋", "answers": [ "しょうぎ" ], "comment": "shogi; Japanese chess; xianqi" },
	{ "question": "尊い", "answers": [ "とうとい", "たっとい" ], "comment": "precious; valuable; priceless; noble; exalted; sacred" },
	{ "question": "尊重", "answers": [ "そんちょう" ], "comment": "respect; esteem; regard" },
	{ "question": "少憩", "answers": [ "しょうけい" ], "comment": "short break; breather; brief recess; rest" },
	{ "question": "屈伸", "answers": [ "くっしん" ], "comment": "bending and stretching (exercise); flexing and extending" },
	{ "question": "屈託", "answers": [ "くったく" ], "comment": "worry; care; concern\nennui; boredom" },
	{ "question": "屈辱", "answers": [ "くつじょく" ], "comment": "disgrace; humiliation" },
	{ "question": "届く", "answers": [ "とどく" ], "comment": "to reach; to arrive; to get through; to get at\nto be attentive; to pay attention\nto be delivered; to carry (e.g. sound)" },
	{ "question": "山岳", "answers": [ "さんがく" ], "comment": "mountains" },
	{ "question": "山菜採り", "answers": [ "さんさいとり" ], "comment": "collecting edible wild plants; gathering edible wild plants" },
	{ "question": "岐路", "answers": [ "きろ" ], "comment": "forked road; crossroads" },
	{ "question": "岳父", "answers": [ "がくふ" ], "comment": "(man's) father-in-law; father of one's wife" },
	{ "question": "峡谷", "answers": [ "きょうこく" ], "comment": "glen; ravine; gorge; canyon" },
	{ "question": "崩れる", "answers": [ "くずれる" ], "comment": "to collapse; to crumble\nto get out of shape; to lose one's shape; to become disorganized; to become untidy\nto break down; to be thrown into disarray\nto crash (stock market); to slump; to decline\nto break money into small change\nto turn bad (e.g. weather); to change for the worse; to deteriorate" },
	{ "question": "崩壊", "answers": [ "ほうかい" ], "comment": "collapse; crumbling; breaking down; caving in\ndecay" },
	{ "question": "崩落", "answers": [ "ほうらく" ], "comment": "collapse; break; cave-in; crash; (market) decline" },
	{ "question": "工房", "answers": [ "こうぼう" ], "comment": "workshop; studio; atelier" },
	{ "question": "巧み", "answers": [ "たくみ" ], "comment": "skillful; adroit; dexterous; masterful; clever; ingenious; cunning" },
	{ "question": "帆柱", "answers": [ "ほばしら" ], "comment": "mast" },
	{ "question": "帆船", "answers": [ "はんせん", "ほぶね" ], "comment": "sailing ship; sailing boat; sailing vessel" },
	{ "question": "希少", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "scarce; rare" },
	{ "question": "帝国", "answers": [ "ていこく" ], "comment": "empire\nimperial" },
	{ "question": "師匠", "answers": [ "ししょう" ], "comment": "master; teacher\ncoach who owns his stable" },
	{ "question": "帰属", "answers": [ "きぞく" ], "comment": "belonging; ascription; attribution; imputation; possession; jurisdiction\nreversion; return; restoration" },
	{ "question": "帳簿", "answers": [ "ちょうぼ" ], "comment": "account book; register; ledger" },
	{ "question": "常駐", "answers": [ "じょうちゅう" ], "comment": "staying permanently; being stationed; resident" },
	{ "question": "幻", "answers": [ "まぼろし" ], "comment": "phantom; vision; illusion; dream; apparition" },
	{ "question": "幻滅", "answers": [ "げんめつ" ], "comment": "disillusionment" },
	{ "question": "幼い", "answers": [ "おさない" ], "comment": "very young\nchildish; immature" },
	{ "question": "幼稚", "answers": [ "ようち" ], "comment": "infancy\nchildish; infantile; immature; primitive" },
	{ "question": "幽谷", "answers": [ "ゆうこく" ], "comment": "deep ravine; glen" },
	{ "question": "幽霊", "answers": [ "ゆうれい" ], "comment": "ghost; specter; spectre; apparition; phantom" },
	{ "question": "廉価", "answers": [ "れんか" ], "comment": "low price" },
	{ "question": "廊下", "answers": [ "ろうか" ], "comment": "corridor; hallway; passageway" },
	{ "question": "延ばす", "answers": [ "のばす" ], "comment": "to grow long (e.g. hair, nails)\nto lengthen; to extend; to stretch\nto reach out; to hold out\nto straighten; to smooth out\nto spread evenly (dough, cream, etc.)\nto dilute; to thin out\nto postpone\nto prolong\nto strengthen; to develop; to expand" },
	{ "question": "弧", "answers": [ "こ" ], "comment": "arc" },
	{ "question": "弧状", "answers": [ "こじょう" ], "comment": "in form of arch" },
	{ "question": "弱冠", "answers": [ "じゃっかん" ], "comment": "aged 20\nyouthfulness" },
	{ "question": "強奪", "answers": [ "ごうだつ" ], "comment": "pillage; seizure; hijacking; plunder; extortion" },
	{ "question": "彩色", "answers": [ "さいしき" ], "comment": "colouring; coloring; colouration; coloration; painting" },
	{ "question": "彫り", "answers": [ "ほり" ], "comment": "carving; engraving\nchiselled features" },
	{ "question": "彫刻", "answers": [ "ちょうこく" ], "comment": "carving; engraving; sculpture" },
	{ "question": "彫金", "answers": [ "ちょうきん" ], "comment": "metal carving; engraving" },
	{ "question": "待ち焦がれる", "answers": [ "まちこがれる" ], "comment": "to long for" },
	{ "question": "待遇", "answers": [ "たいぐう" ], "comment": "treatment; reception; service\nworking conditions; salary; pay; remuneration" },
	{ "question": "徐々", "answers": [ "じょじょ" ], "comment": "gradually; steadily; quietly; slowly; little by little\nsoon" },
	{ "question": "徐行", "answers": [ "じょこう" ], "comment": "going slowly" },
	{ "question": "従う", "answers": [ "したがう" ], "comment": "to abide (by the rules); to obey; to follow; to accompany" },
	{ "question": "心境", "answers": [ "しんきょう" ], "comment": "mental state" },
	{ "question": "心憎い", "answers": [ "こころにくい" ], "comment": "refined; admirable; superb" },
	{ "question": "必ず", "answers": [ "かならず" ], "comment": "always; without exception; necessarily; certainly; without fail; positively; invariably" },
	{ "question": "忌引き", "answers": [ "きびき" ], "comment": "absence from work (school) due to mourning" },
	{ "question": "忌避", "answers": [ "きひ" ], "comment": "evasion; shirking; avoidance\nchallenge; (taking) exception" },
	{ "question": "忘れる", "answers": [ "わすれる" ], "comment": "to forget; to leave carelessly; to be forgetful of; to forget about; to forget (an article)" },
	{ "question": "応募", "answers": [ "おうぼ" ], "comment": "application; subscription; entry (competition, raffle, etc.); enlistment" },
	{ "question": "快諾", "answers": [ "かいだく" ], "comment": "ready consent" },
	{ "question": "怠ける", "answers": [ "なまける" ], "comment": "to be idle; to slacken\nto neglect (e.g. one's work)" },
	{ "question": "怠る", "answers": [ "おこたる" ], "comment": "to be negligent in doing something; to shirk; to be off one's guard" },
	{ "question": "怠慢", "answers": [ "たいまん" ], "comment": "negligence; neglect; carelessness; procrastination" },
	{ "question": "怪しい", "answers": [ "あやしい" ], "comment": "suspicious; dubious; doubtful; dodgy; suspicious (referring to a potential amorous relation); dangerous (e.g. financial situation); ominous (e.g. weather); strange; shady; fishy\ncharming; bewitching; mysterious" },
	{ "question": "怪物", "answers": [ "かいぶつ" ], "comment": "monster" },
	{ "question": "怪談", "answers": [ "かいだん" ], "comment": "ghost story" },
	{ "question": "恋慕", "answers": [ "れんぼ" ], "comment": "love; attachment; tender emotions; falling in love" },
	{ "question": "恐悦", "answers": [ "きょうえつ" ], "comment": "delight" },
	{ "question": "恩赦", "answers": [ "おんしゃ" ], "comment": "amnesty; pardon" },
	{ "question": "悔しい", "answers": [ "くやしい" ], "comment": "vexing; annoying; frustrating; regrettable; mortifying" },
	{ "question": "悔やむ", "answers": [ "くやむ" ], "comment": "to mourn; to lament\nto be sorry; to regret; to repent" },
	{ "question": "悔恨", "answers": [ "かいこん" ], "comment": "regret" },
	{ "question": "悔悟", "answers": [ "かいご" ], "comment": "remorse; repentance" },
	{ "question": "悟る", "answers": [ "さとる" ], "comment": "to perceive; to sense; to discern\nto understand; to comprehend; to realize\nto attain enlightenment" },
	{ "question": "悲哀", "answers": [ "ひあい" ], "comment": "sorrow; grief; sadness" },
	{ "question": "愛憎", "answers": [ "あいぞう" ], "comment": "love and hate; likes and dislikes" },
	{ "question": "感慨", "answers": [ "かんがい" ], "comment": "strong feelings; deep emotion" },
	{ "question": "慈善", "answers": [ "じぜん" ], "comment": "charity; philanthropy" },
	{ "question": "慈悲", "answers": [ "じひ" ], "comment": "compassion (e.g. of Buddha); benevolence; charity; mercy\nHodgson's hawk-cuckoo (Cuculus fugax); Horsfield's hawk cuckoo" },
	{ "question": "慌ただしい", "answers": [ "あわただしい" ], "comment": "busy; hurried; confused; flurried" },
	{ "question": "慌てる", "answers": [ "あわてる" ], "comment": "to become confused (disconcerted, disorganized, disorganised); to be flustered; to panic\nto be in a hurry; to rush" },
	{ "question": "慕う", "answers": [ "したう" ], "comment": "to yearn for; to long for; to pine for; to miss; to love dearly; to adore\nto follow (someone)\nto idolize (for virtue, learning, status, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "慣れる", "answers": [ "なれる" ], "comment": "to get used to; to grow accustomed to; to become familiar with\nto become skilled in; to become experienced at\nto become tame; to become domesticated" },
	{ "question": "慨嘆", "answers": [ "がいたん" ], "comment": "deploring; lamentation; regret; complaint" },
	{ "question": "慰める", "answers": [ "なぐさめる" ], "comment": "to comfort; to console; to amuse" },
	{ "question": "慰安", "answers": [ "いあん" ], "comment": "solace; relaxation" },
	{ "question": "慰留", "answers": [ "いりゅう" ], "comment": "dissuasion from resigning or leaving" },
	{ "question": "憂い", "answers": [ "うれい", "うい" ], "comment": "unhappy; sad; gloomy\nsorrow; grief; anguish; distress\ntrouble; affliction; anxiety; fear; misgivings" },
	{ "question": "憂慮", "answers": [ "ゆうりょ" ], "comment": "anxiety; concern; fear" },
	{ "question": "憂色", "answers": [ "ゆうしょく" ], "comment": "melancholy air; anxious look; traces of sorrow; gloom" },
	{ "question": "憩い", "answers": [ "いこい" ], "comment": "rest" },
	{ "question": "房", "answers": [ "ふさ" ], "comment": "tuft; tassel\nbunch (of grapes, etc.)\nsection (of an orange, etc.)\nchamber; room\nhome of a monk; monk\nChinese \"room\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "手厚い", "answers": [ "てあつい" ], "comment": "courteous; cordial; warm" },
	{ "question": "手錠", "answers": [ "てじょう" ], "comment": "handcuffs; manacles" },
	{ "question": "批判", "answers": [ "ひはん" ], "comment": "criticism; judgement; judgment; comment" },
	{ "question": "承諾", "answers": [ "しょうだく" ], "comment": "consent; acquiescence; agreement" },
	{ "question": "抑揚", "answers": [ "よくよう" ], "comment": "intonation; accent; modulation; inflection" },
	{ "question": "抑止", "answers": [ "よくし" ], "comment": "check; checkmate; stave off; control; restraint; inhibit; deterrent; deterrence" },
	{ "question": "投獄", "answers": [ "とうごく" ], "comment": "imprisonment" },
	{ "question": "折れる", "answers": [ "おれる" ], "comment": "to break; to be broken; to snap; to fracture\nto be folded\nto give in; to back down; to yield; to submit\nto turn (a corner)" },
	{ "question": "折半", "answers": [ "せっぱん" ], "comment": "halving; splitting evenly; sharing equally" },
	{ "question": "抜粋", "answers": [ "ばっすい" ], "comment": "extract; excerpt; selection" },
	{ "question": "抽出", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゅつ" ], "comment": "extraction; abstraction\nselection (from a group); sampling; eduction" },
	{ "question": "抽象", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "abstract" },
	{ "question": "拘束", "answers": [ "こうそく" ], "comment": "restriction; restraint; binding; constraint" },
	{ "question": "拘置所", "answers": [ "こうちしょ" ], "comment": "prison; detention house; detention center; jail" },
	{ "question": "拝む", "answers": [ "おがむ" ], "comment": "to assume the posture of praying; to press the palms and fingers of both hands together; to do reverence (e.g. before a statue of the Buddha); to pay one's respects\nto beg; to make a supplication\nto see (something or someone of high status)" },
	{ "question": "挙措", "answers": [ "きょそ" ], "comment": "behavior; behaviour; manner" },
	{ "question": "捕鯨", "answers": [ "ほげい" ], "comment": "whaling; whale fishing" },
	{ "question": "掃討", "answers": [ "そうとう" ], "comment": "cleaning up; sweeping up; mopping up" },
	{ "question": "授かる", "answers": [ "さずかる" ], "comment": "to be awarded (e.g. a prize); to be given an award; to receive (e.g. a title)\nto be gifted or endowed (e.g. with a talent)\nto be blessed (e.g. with a child)\nto be initiated (e.g. into a secret)" },
	{ "question": "掌中", "answers": [ "しょうちゅう" ], "comment": "in the hand; (something) easily manipulated" },
	{ "question": "掌握", "answers": [ "しょうあく" ], "comment": "grasping; seizing; holding; commanding; having control over" },
	{ "question": "排他", "answers": [ "はいた" ], "comment": "exclusion" },
	{ "question": "排斥", "answers": [ "はいせき" ], "comment": "rejection; expulsion; boycott; ostracism" },
	{ "question": "排除", "answers": [ "はいじょ" ], "comment": "exclusion; removal; rejection; elimination; abatement; lifting (sanctions, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "掘削", "answers": [ "くっさく" ], "comment": "digging out; excavation" },
	{ "question": "掛かり", "answers": [ "がかり" ], "comment": "starting; engaging\nexpenses; costs\nattack (esp. a corner approach in the game of go)\nbarb\ncharge; duty; person in charge; official; clerk\ntaking a quantity (of time, people, etc.)\nsimilar to ...\ndependent on ...; reliant on ...\nwhile ...; when ...; in the midst of ..." },
	{ "question": "採択", "answers": [ "さいたく" ], "comment": "adoption; selection; choice" },
	{ "question": "控える", "answers": [ "ひかえる" ], "comment": "to be temperate in; to refrain; to abstain; to hold back; to restrain oneself from excessive ...\nto make notes; to jot down (e.g. phone number)\nto be in preparation for; to be in waiting for\nto be soon; to be in the offing\nto be in a close relationship (e.g. as a backer, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "推挙", "answers": [ "すいきょ" ], "comment": "recommendation; nomination" },
	{ "question": "措置", "answers": [ "そち" ], "comment": "measure; step; action" },
	{ "question": "掲げる", "answers": [ "かかげる" ], "comment": "to publish; to print; to carry (an article) Ichidan verb,transitive verb\nto put up; to hang out; to hoist; to fly (a sail); to float (a flag, kite, etc.)\nto tuck up (e.g. sleeves); to roll up\nto tout (a principle, plan, etc.); to adopt (a slogan)\nto stoke a fire; to fan a flame" },
	{ "question": "掲載", "answers": [ "けいさい" ], "comment": "publication (e.g. article in paper); appearance; insertion\nto insert (e.g. an article); to run (e.g. in a newspaper); to carry (e.g. an article); to post (e.g. on the Web)" },
	{ "question": "揚げたて", "answers": [ "あげたて" ], "comment": "just taken out of the deep fryer; freshly deep-fried" },
	{ "question": "換気", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "ventilation" },
	{ "question": "揺れ", "answers": [ "ゆれ" ], "comment": "shaking; shake; jolt; jolting; vibration; tremor; flickering\nunsettledness; instability; vacillating; wavering\nexistence of multiple spellings, pronunciations, usages, etc. for a single word" },
	{ "question": "損なう", "answers": [ "そこなう" ], "comment": "to harm; to hurt; to injure; to damage; to spoil; to mar\nto fail to ...; to miss one's opportunity to ..." },
	{ "question": "携わる", "answers": [ "たずさわる" ], "comment": "to engage in; to participate; to take part" },
	{ "question": "搾る", "answers": [ "しぼる" ], "comment": "to wring (towel, rag); to squeeze\nto squeeze (fruit to extract juice); to press; to extract; to milk; to express milk\nto rack (one's brains); to strain (one's voice)\nto extort; to exploit\nto chew out; to reprimand severely; to rake over the coals; to give a sound scolding; to tell someone off; to scold; to rebuke\nto drill into; to train\nto narrow down (one's focus); to whittle down\nto gather up (curtain, etc.); to tighten (drawstring)\nto stop down (lens)\nto turn down (e.g. radio)\nto bend (bow); to draw\nto hold down; to constrict; to immobilize" },
	{ "question": "摂取", "answers": [ "せっしゅ" ], "comment": "intake; absorption; adoption\nassimilation" },
	{ "question": "摂理", "answers": [ "せつり" ], "comment": "(divine) providence; dispensation" },
	{ "question": "撮る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to take (a photo)\nto record (video, audio, etc.); to make (a film)" },
	{ "question": "撮影", "answers": [ "さつえい" ], "comment": "photography (still or motion); photographing; filming; shooting; (video) recording" },
	{ "question": "撮要", "answers": [ "さつよう" ], "comment": "outline; summary; compendium" },
	{ "question": "擁立", "answers": [ "ようりつ" ], "comment": "backing (for a position); support" },
	{ "question": "擁護", "answers": [ "ようご" ], "comment": "protection; advocacy; support; defence; championship; vindication\nto protect (e.g. rights, etc.); to advocate (e.g. free trade, etc.); to support" },
	{ "question": "操作", "answers": [ "そうさ" ], "comment": "operation; management; handling\nmanipulating to one's benefit" },
	{ "question": "擦り", "answers": [ "すり" ], "comment": "grazing; touching lightly\nsqueezing (someone for money); percentage; kickback\nrubbing; scrubbing; scraping" },
	{ "question": "擦過傷", "answers": [ "さっかしょう" ], "comment": "abrasion; scratch" },
	{ "question": "支障", "answers": [ "ししょう" ], "comment": "obstacle; hindrance; impediment; difficulty" },
	{ "question": "改めて", "answers": [ "あらためて" ], "comment": "another time; again; over again; once again; anew\nformally; especially; intentionally; deliberately" },
	{ "question": "改訂", "answers": [ "かいてい" ], "comment": "revision (of text); alteration; change" },
	{ "question": "放棄", "answers": [ "ほうき" ], "comment": "abandonment; renunciation; resignation; abdication (responsibility, right)" },
	{ "question": "放浪", "answers": [ "ほうろう" ], "comment": "wandering" },
	{ "question": "故", "answers": [ "ゆえ" ], "comment": "used item; secondhand item\nold; used; previous\nthe late (deceased)\nreason; cause; circumstances\nintentionally; deliberately\nespecially; particularly\nformer; ex-; past; one-time" },
	{ "question": "敢行", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "decisive action" },
	{ "question": "敬う", "answers": [ "うやまう" ], "comment": "to show respect; to honour; to honor" },
	{ "question": "敬慕", "answers": [ "けいぼ" ], "comment": "love and respect" },
	{ "question": "数隻", "answers": [ "すうせき" ], "comment": "several (boats)" },
	{ "question": "断つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to sever; to cut off\nto suppress; to eradicate; to exterminate\nto abstain (from); to give up" },
	{ "question": "断り", "answers": [ "ことわり" ], "comment": "notice; notification; warning\npermission; consent\nrejection; refusal; nonacceptance; declination; declining\nexcuse; plea" },
	{ "question": "施す", "answers": [ "ほどこす" ], "comment": "to give (time, money, goods); to donate\nto do; to perform; to conduct\nto apply (processing, makeup, etc.); to add (e.g. ornamentation, annotation)\nto sow; to seed; to scatter (e.g. fertilizer); to sprinkle\nto spread far and wide" },
	{ "question": "施設", "answers": [ "しせつ" ], "comment": "institution; establishment; facility\n(army) engineer" },
	{ "question": "既に", "answers": [ "すでに" ], "comment": "already; too late" },
	{ "question": "既成", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "established; completed; existing" },
	{ "question": "既知", "answers": [ "きち" ], "comment": "already known; well-known" },
	{ "question": "昇給", "answers": [ "しょうきゅう" ], "comment": "salary raise" },
	{ "question": "昇進", "answers": [ "しょうしん" ], "comment": "promotion; advancement; rising in rank" },
	{ "question": "易しい", "answers": [ "やさしい" ], "comment": "easy; plain; simple" },
	{ "question": "暖房", "answers": [ "だんぼう" ], "comment": "(indoor) heating" },
	{ "question": "暫定", "answers": [ "ざんてい" ], "comment": "tentative; temporary" },
	{ "question": "暫時", "answers": [ "ざんじ" ], "comment": "short while" },
	{ "question": "暴れる", "answers": [ "あばれる" ], "comment": "to act violently; to rage; to struggle; to be riotous" },
	{ "question": "有効", "answers": [ "ゆうこう" ], "comment": "valid; effective\nyuko (judo)" },
	{ "question": "朗らか", "answers": [ "ほがらか" ], "comment": "bright; cheerful; melodious" },
	{ "question": "朗詠", "answers": [ "ろうえい" ], "comment": "recitation (of Japanese or Chinese poem)" },
	{ "question": "本邦", "answers": [ "ほんぽう" ], "comment": "this country; our country" },
	{ "question": "束縛", "answers": [ "そくばく" ], "comment": "restraint; restriction; fetters; yoke; shackles\nbinding; confinement with rope" },
	{ "question": "枚挙", "answers": [ "まいきょ" ], "comment": "enumeration" },
	{ "question": "果断", "answers": [ "かだん" ], "comment": "decisive; resolute; drastic" },
	{ "question": "架ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "to suspend between two points; to build (a bridge, etc.); to put up on something (e.g. legs up on table)" },
	{ "question": "架空", "answers": [ "かくう" ], "comment": "aerial; overhead\nfictitious; imaginary; fanciful; fabricated" },
	{ "question": "某", "answers": [ "ぼう" ], "comment": "someone; unknown person\nI; personal pronoun (used by samurai)\ncertain; one\ncertain amount; some\ncertain person; Mr So-and-so; a certain ...\nI; me" },
	{ "question": "栄冠", "answers": [ "えいかん" ], "comment": "laurels; garland" },
	{ "question": "校閲", "answers": [ "こうえつ" ], "comment": "revision; proofreading" },
	{ "question": "株主", "answers": [ "かぶぬし" ], "comment": "shareholder; stockholder" },
	{ "question": "株価", "answers": [ "かぶか" ], "comment": "stock prices" },
	{ "question": "格段", "answers": [ "かくだん" ], "comment": "special; exceptional; remarkable" },
	{ "question": "桑", "answers": [ "くわ" ], "comment": "mulberry (tree)" },
	{ "question": "桑畑", "answers": [ "くわばたけ" ], "comment": "mulberry field; mulberry plantation" },
	{ "question": "棋士", "answers": [ "きし" ], "comment": "shogi player; go player" },
	{ "question": "検尿", "answers": [ "けんにょう" ], "comment": "urinalysis" },
	{ "question": "極めて", "answers": [ "きわめて" ], "comment": "exceedingly; extremely; decisively" },
	{ "question": "楼閣", "answers": [ "ろうかく" ], "comment": "multistoried building" },
	{ "question": "概略", "answers": [ "がいりゃく" ], "comment": "outline; summary; gist; in brief" },
	{ "question": "概要", "answers": [ "がいよう" ], "comment": "outline; summary; overview; abridgment; synopsis" },
	{ "question": "構える", "answers": [ "かまえる" ], "comment": "to set up (a house, store, etc.); to build; to establish; to run; to maintain\nto have at the ready (e.g. a gun); to hold in preparation (e.g. a camera); to prepare in advance (e.g. a meal)\nto adopt a posture; to assume a stance; to stand ready; to be poised for\nto put on an air; to assume an attitude\nto stiffen; to tense up; to become formal\nto fabricate in order to deceive; to make up; to feign\nto plan; to scheme" },
	{ "question": "模倣", "answers": [ "もほう" ], "comment": "imitation; copying" },
	{ "question": "横領", "answers": [ "おうりょう" ], "comment": "embezzlement; misappropriation; usurpation" },
	{ "question": "欠乏", "answers": [ "けつぼう" ], "comment": "want; shortage; famine" },
	{ "question": "欠如", "answers": [ "けつじょ" ], "comment": "lack; privation; deficiency" },
	{ "question": "欧州", "answers": [ "おうしゅう" ], "comment": "Europe" },
	{ "question": "欧米", "answers": [ "おうべい" ], "comment": "Europe and America; the West" },
	{ "question": "欺く", "answers": [ "あざむく" ], "comment": "to deceive; to delude; to trick; to fool\nto be as ... as ... (e.g. \"as bright as day\", \"as beautiful as a rose\")" },
	{ "question": "歌姫", "answers": [ "うたひめ" ], "comment": "songstress; diva" },
	{ "question": "殊勝", "answers": [ "しゅしょう" ], "comment": "admirable; laudable" },
	{ "question": "殊更", "answers": [ "ことさら" ], "comment": "intentionally; deliberately\nespecially; particularly" },
	{ "question": "残虐", "answers": [ "ざんぎゃく" ], "comment": "cruelty; brutality" },
	{ "question": "殴る", "answers": [ "なぐる" ], "comment": "to strike; to hit; to beat; to punch" },
	{ "question": "段位", "answers": [ "だんい" ], "comment": "dan rank (in martial arts, go, etc.); advanced rank; grade of black belt" },
	{ "question": "殺伐", "answers": [ "さつばつ" ], "comment": "bloodthirsty; brutal; savage" },
	{ "question": "気炎", "answers": [ "きえん" ], "comment": "high spirits; big talking" },
	{ "question": "水墨画", "answers": [ "すいぼくが" ], "comment": "India-ink painting" },
	{ "question": "求刑", "answers": [ "きゅうけい" ], "comment": "recommended sentence; prosecution's demand for punishment" },
	{ "question": "決済", "answers": [ "けっさい" ], "comment": "settlement; payment of account" },
	{ "question": "決裂", "answers": [ "けつれつ" ], "comment": "breakdown; rupture" },
	{ "question": "没頭", "answers": [ "ぼっとう" ], "comment": "immersing oneself; devoting oneself; giving oneself up entirely to" },
	{ "question": "河畔", "answers": [ "かはん" ], "comment": "riverside" },
	{ "question": "洗練", "answers": [ "せんれん" ], "comment": "polish; refinement" },
	{ "question": "浅瀬", "answers": [ "あさせ" ], "comment": "shoal; shallows; sand bar; ford" },
	{ "question": "浪費", "answers": [ "ろうひ" ], "comment": "waste; extravagance" },
	{ "question": "海峡", "answers": [ "かいきょう" ], "comment": "channel (e.g. between two land masses); strait" },
	{ "question": "海賊", "answers": [ "かいぞく" ], "comment": "pirate; sea robber" },
	{ "question": "浸す", "answers": [ "ひたす" ], "comment": "to soak; to dip; to steep; to immerse\nto moisten; to wet" },
	{ "question": "液晶", "answers": [ "えきしょう" ], "comment": "liquid crystal" },
	{ "question": "深刻", "answers": [ "しんこく" ], "comment": "serious; severe; grave; acute" },
	{ "question": "混ぜる", "answers": [ "まぜる" ], "comment": "to mix; to stir; to blend" },
	{ "question": "混迷", "answers": [ "こんめい" ], "comment": "turmoil; chaos; confusion" },
	{ "question": "添削", "answers": [ "てんさく" ], "comment": "correction; looking over; touching up" },
	{ "question": "清廉", "answers": [ "せいれん" ], "comment": "honesty; integrity; purity and unselfishness" },
	{ "question": "測る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to measure; to weigh; to survey; to time (sound, gauge, estimate)\nto conjecture; to infer; to surmise" },
	{ "question": "湖畔", "answers": [ "こはん" ], "comment": "lake shore" },
	{ "question": "湾曲", "answers": [ "わんきょく" ], "comment": "curve; bend; crook" },
	{ "question": "湿原", "answers": [ "しつげん" ], "comment": "marshy grassland; wetlands" },
	{ "question": "満喫", "answers": [ "まんきつ" ], "comment": "having enough of (food, drink, etc.); having one's fill\nfully enjoying" },
	{ "question": "滅ぶ", "answers": [ "ほろぶ" ] },
	{ "question": "滅多", "answers": [ "めった" ], "comment": "thoughtless; reckless; careless; rash\nseldom (with neg. verb); rare\nordinary; usual; common\nexcessive; immoderate; extreme" },
	{ "question": "滑り", "answers": [ "すべり" ], "comment": "sliding; slipping\nslime; mucus; sliminess; viscous liquid" },
	{ "question": "滝", "answers": [ "たき" ], "comment": "waterfall\nrapids" },
	{ "question": "滞る", "answers": [ "とどこおる" ], "comment": "to stagnate; to be delayed; to be left undone\nto be overdue (of a payment); to fall into arrears; to be outstanding" },
	{ "question": "滞在", "answers": [ "たいざい" ], "comment": "stay; sojourn" },
	{ "question": "漂う", "answers": [ "ただよう" ], "comment": "to drift; to float\nto waft (e.g. a scent); to hang in the air\nto be in the air (e.g. a feeling or mood)\nto wander; to walk around aimlessly\nto be unsteady; to be unstable\nto falter; to flinch; to wince\nto live in unreliable circumstances" },
	{ "question": "漂泊", "answers": [ "ひょうはく" ], "comment": "roaming; drifting about; wandering" },
	{ "question": "漂着", "answers": [ "ひょうちゃく" ], "comment": "drifting ashore" },
	{ "question": "漏れる", "answers": [ "もれる" ], "comment": "to leak out; to escape; to come through; to shine through; to filter out\nto find expression; to give vent\nto leak out; to be divulged; to be disclosed\nto be omitted; to be left out; to be excluded; to be not included" },
	{ "question": "漏電", "answers": [ "ろうでん" ], "comment": "short circuit; leakage (of electricity); electrical fault" },
	{ "question": "演奏", "answers": [ "えんそう" ], "comment": "musical performance" },
	{ "question": "潔癖", "answers": [ "けっぺき" ], "comment": "fastidiousness; love of cleanliness" },
	{ "question": "潜伏", "answers": [ "せんぷく" ], "comment": "concealment; hiding; ambush\nincubation; latency; dormancy" },
	{ "question": "潜入", "answers": [ "せんにゅう" ], "comment": "infiltration; sneaking in" },
	{ "question": "潜在", "answers": [ "せんざい" ], "comment": "potentiality; dormancy; latency" },
	{ "question": "潤い", "answers": [ "うるおい" ], "comment": "moisture; damp; wetness\nrichness; warmth; gain; profit\nfinancial leeway" },
	{ "question": "潤沢", "answers": [ "じゅんたく" ], "comment": "abundant; ample; plentiful; affluent\nlustrous; glossy" },
	{ "question": "潤滑", "answers": [ "じゅんかつ" ], "comment": "lubrication; smoothness" },
	{ "question": "潮時", "answers": [ "しおどき" ], "comment": "tidal hour\nright time; favourable opportunity (favorable)" },
	{ "question": "激しい", "answers": [ "はげしい" ], "comment": "violent; furious; tempestuous\nextreme; intense; fierce; strong\nfervent; vehement\nincessant; relentless\nprecipitous; steep" },
	{ "question": "激励", "answers": [ "げきれい" ], "comment": "encouragement" },
	{ "question": "濃紺", "answers": [ "のうこん" ], "comment": "dark blue" },
	{ "question": "濫伐", "answers": [ "らんばつ" ], "comment": "reckless deforestation; overcutting of forests" },
	{ "question": "濫用", "answers": [ "らんよう" ], "comment": "abuse; misuse; misappropriation; using to excess" },
	{ "question": "瀬踏み", "answers": [ "せぶみ" ], "comment": "sounding out; measuring the depths (of a river)" },
	{ "question": "災い", "answers": [ "わざわい" ], "comment": "calamity; catastrophe; misfortune" },
	{ "question": "炉端", "answers": [ "ろばた" ], "comment": "fireside; hearth; by the fire" },
	{ "question": "炊く", "answers": [ "たく" ], "comment": "to cook (grains, e.g. rice)\nto boil; to simmer; to stew; to seethe [Kansai-ben]" },
	{ "question": "炭鉱", "answers": [ "たんこう" ], "comment": "coal mine; coal pit" },
	{ "question": "無謀", "answers": [ "むぼう" ], "comment": "reckless; thoughtless; rash; ill-advised; impulsive; mad (scheme, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "焦点", "answers": [ "しょうてん" ], "comment": "focus (e.g. photographic); focal point" },
	{ "question": "焦燥", "answers": [ "しょうそう" ], "comment": "impatience; uneasiness; irritation; fretfulness" },
	{ "question": "片付け", "answers": [ "かたづけ" ], "comment": "tidying up; finishing" },
	{ "question": "片道", "answers": [ "かたみち" ], "comment": "one-way (trip)\none-way ticket" },
	{ "question": "特殊", "answers": [ "とくしゅ" ], "comment": "special; particular; peculiar; unique" },
	{ "question": "特許", "answers": [ "とっきょ" ], "comment": "patent; special permission; licence (license); concession; franchise; charter\nproprietary" },
	{ "question": "犠打", "answers": [ "ぎだ" ], "comment": "sacrifice fly; bunt" },
	{ "question": "犠牲", "answers": [ "ぎせい" ], "comment": "victim; sacrifice; scapegoat" },
	{ "question": "狩猟", "answers": [ "しゅりょう" ], "comment": "hunting" },
	{ "question": "独り善がり", "answers": [ "ひとりよがり" ], "comment": "complacent; self-satisfied; self-important; conceited; self-righteous" },
	{ "question": "猟師", "answers": [ "りょうし" ], "comment": "hunter; huntsman" },
	{ "question": "甲", "answers": [ "こう" ], "comment": "armor; armour\nhelmet (of armor, armour); headpiece\ncarapace; shell\n1st in rank; grade A\ninstep; back of hand\nthe A party (e.g. in a contract); the first party; plaintiff (label in legal documents)\ntreble range (in Japanese music); high note\nfirst sign of the Chinese calendar" },
	{ "question": "甲乙", "answers": [ "こうおつ" ], "comment": "A and B; excellent and good; similarity\ndiscrimination; discernment; distinction\nfirst and second parties (in legal contexts)" },
	{ "question": "申請", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "application; request; petition" },
	{ "question": "画壇", "answers": [ "がだん" ], "comment": "artists' world; painting circles" },
	{ "question": "画廊", "answers": [ "がろう" ], "comment": "art gallery (esp. artworks for sale); picture gallery" },
	{ "question": "留守", "answers": [ "るす" ], "comment": "absence; being away from home\nhouse-sitting; house-sitter\nbeing left unattended to (of one's studies, etc.); neglecting" },
	{ "question": "畜産", "answers": [ "ちくさん" ], "comment": "animal husbandry" },
	{ "question": "疑い", "answers": [ "うたがい" ], "comment": "doubt; question; uncertainty; skepticism; scepticism; suspicion; distrust" },
	{ "question": "疑う", "answers": [ "うたがう" ], "comment": "to doubt; to distrust; to be suspicious of; to suspect" },
	{ "question": "疾走", "answers": [ "しっそう" ], "comment": "sprint; dash; scampering" },
	{ "question": "疾風", "answers": [ "しっぷう" ], "comment": "gale; strong wind; swift wind; fresh breeze (Beaufort scale)" },
	{ "question": "疾駆", "answers": [ "しっく" ], "comment": "riding fast; driving a horse fast" },
	{ "question": "痛める", "answers": [ "いためる" ], "comment": "to hurt; to injure; to cause pain\nto harm; to damage; to spoil\nto worry; to bother; to be grieved over; to afflict\nto cause financial loss; to hurt one's pocket\nto hurt; to ache" },
	{ "question": "痛恨", "answers": [ "つうこん" ], "comment": "regretful; sorrowful; bitter\ncontrition" },
	{ "question": "発酵", "answers": [ "はっこう" ], "comment": "fermentation; zymosis" },
	{ "question": "皇帝", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "emperor" },
	{ "question": "盗賊", "answers": [ "とうぞく" ], "comment": "thief; robber; burglar; bandit" },
	{ "question": "相伴", "answers": [ "しょうばん" ], "comment": "partaking; participating; taking part in; sharing (something with someone)" },
	{ "question": "相克", "answers": [ "そうこく" ], "comment": "rivalry" },
	{ "question": "省く", "answers": [ "はぶく" ], "comment": "to omit; to leave out; to exclude; to eliminate\nto curtail; to save; to cut down; to economize; to economise" },
	{ "question": "看過", "answers": [ "かんか" ], "comment": "overlooking; turning a blind eye" },
	{ "question": "眼下", "answers": [ "がんか" ], "comment": "under one's eyes; below" },
	{ "question": "石碑", "answers": [ "せきひ" ], "comment": "stone monument" },
	{ "question": "砂場", "answers": [ "すなば" ], "comment": "sand pit; sandbox" },
	{ "question": "破棄", "answers": [ "はき" ], "comment": "tearing up and discarding (e.g. documents); disposal (e.g. weaponry); destruction\nannulment; cancellation; abrogation; voiding; breaking (e.g. treaty)\nreversal (of an original ruling)" },
	{ "question": "破裂", "answers": [ "はれつ" ], "comment": "explosion; rupture; break off" },
	{ "question": "確かめる", "answers": [ "たしかめる" ], "comment": "to ascertain; to check; to make sure" },
	{ "question": "確信", "answers": [ "かくしん" ], "comment": "conviction; belief; confidence" },
	{ "question": "礎石", "answers": [ "そせき" ], "comment": "foundation stone; cornerstone" },
	{ "question": "祝う", "answers": [ "いわう" ], "comment": "to congratulate; to celebrate; to observe (a festival)" },
	{ "question": "祝宴", "answers": [ "しゅくえん" ], "comment": "celebratory banquet; feast" },
	{ "question": "神髄", "answers": [ "しんずい" ], "comment": "essence; quintessence; spirit; soul; heart; pith; pith and marrow" },
	{ "question": "福祉", "answers": [ "ふくし" ], "comment": "welfare; well-being; social welfare; social security; social service" },
	{ "question": "秘境", "answers": [ "ひきょう" ], "comment": "unexplored region; one of the most secluded regions" },
	{ "question": "移籍", "answers": [ "いせき" ], "comment": "changing household registry; transfer (e.g. of one's name in the register)\ntransferring to a different team" },
	{ "question": "程無く", "answers": [ "ほどなく" ], "comment": "soon; before long; shortly thereafter" },
	{ "question": "稚魚", "answers": [ "ちぎょ" ], "comment": "fry; juvenile fish; fingerling" },
	{ "question": "種痘", "answers": [ "しゅとう" ], "comment": "(smallpox) vaccination; inoculation" },
	{ "question": "稲穂", "answers": [ "いなほ" ], "comment": "ear (head) of rice" },
	{ "question": "穂先", "answers": [ "ほさき" ], "comment": "ear (e.g. of wheat)\ntip (e.g. of brush or spear); spearhead" },
	{ "question": "穏やか", "answers": [ "おだやか" ], "comment": "calm; gentle; quiet" },
	{ "question": "穏便", "answers": [ "おんびん" ], "comment": "gentle; peaceable; amicable; quiet\nwithout fuss; simply" },
	{ "question": "突如", "answers": [ "とつじょ" ], "comment": "suddenly; all of a sudden" },
	{ "question": "窒息", "answers": [ "ちっそく" ], "comment": "suffocation; choking; asphyxia" },
	{ "question": "窒素", "answers": [ "ちっそ" ], "comment": "nitrogen (N)" },
	{ "question": "窓", "answers": [ "まど" ], "comment": "window" },
	{ "question": "立証", "answers": [ "りっしょう" ], "comment": "establishing proof; demonstration; substantiation" },
	{ "question": "笑み", "answers": [ "えみ" ], "comment": "smile" },
	{ "question": "符号", "answers": [ "ふごう" ], "comment": "sign; mark; symbol; code\nsign (e.g. positive, negative)" },
	{ "question": "築く", "answers": [ "きずく" ], "comment": "to build; to construct; to erect\nto amass (e.g. fortune); to pile up" },
	{ "question": "篤志家", "answers": [ "とくしか" ], "comment": "volunteer; self-sacrificing person" },
	{ "question": "簡潔", "answers": [ "かんけつ" ], "comment": "brevity; conciseness; simplicity" },
	{ "question": "粋", "answers": [ "いき" ], "comment": "chic; smart; stylish; tasteful; refined; sophisticated; worldly\nconsiderate; understanding; sympathetic\nessence; the best; the cream" },
	{ "question": "粗大", "answers": [ "そだい" ], "comment": "coarse; rough; bulky" },
	{ "question": "粘り", "answers": [ "ねばり" ], "comment": "stickiness; viscosity\ntenacity; persistence" },
	{ "question": "粘り強い", "answers": [ "ねばりづよい" ], "comment": "tenacious; persevering; persistent; stubborn; steadfast\nsticky" },
	{ "question": "粘土", "answers": [ "ねんど" ], "comment": "clay" },
	{ "question": "粘着", "answers": [ "ねんちゃく" ], "comment": "cohesion; adhesion" },
	{ "question": "精励", "answers": [ "せいれい" ], "comment": "diligence; industry" },
	{ "question": "精巧", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "elaborate; delicate; exquisite" },
	{ "question": "精粗", "answers": [ "せいそ" ], "comment": "fineness or coarseness; minuteness or roughness" },
	{ "question": "精錬", "answers": [ "せいれん" ], "comment": "refining; refinement; smelting\ntraining" },
	{ "question": "糖尿病", "answers": [ "とうにょうびょう" ], "comment": "diabetes mellitus; sugar diabetes" },
	{ "question": "納める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to dedicate; to make an offering; to pay (fees)\nto supply\nto store\nto finish; to bring to a close\nto restore (something to its place)\nto achieve (e.g. a result)" },
	{ "question": "純粋", "answers": [ "じゅんすい" ], "comment": "pure; true; genuine; unmixed" },
	{ "question": "紛らわしい", "answers": [ "まぎらわしい" ], "comment": "confusing; misleading; equivocal; ambiguous; easily mixed up (e.g. similar words)" },
	{ "question": "紛れる", "answers": [ "まぎれる" ], "comment": "to disappear into; to be lost in; to slip into; to get mixed in among\nto do something under the cover of (confusion, etc.)\nto be almost indistinguishable; to be confusingly similar\nto be diverted from (negative emotions, etc.); to forget about\nto be distracted by; to be too absorbed in" },
	{ "question": "紛争", "answers": [ "ふんそう" ], "comment": "dispute; trouble; strife" },
	{ "question": "紫紺", "answers": [ "しこん" ], "comment": "bluish purple" },
	{ "question": "細胞", "answers": [ "さいぼう" ], "comment": "cell" },
	{ "question": "結晶", "answers": [ "けっしょう" ], "comment": "crystal; crystallization; crystallisation\nfruits (of labor, union, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "絞める", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "to strangle; to constrict" },
	{ "question": "絞る", "answers": [ "しぼる" ], "comment": "to wring (towel, rag); to squeeze\nto squeeze (fruit to extract juice); to press; to extract; to milk; to express milk\nto rack (one's brains); to strain (one's voice)\nto extort; to exploit\nto chew out; to reprimand severely; to rake over the coals; to give a sound scolding; to tell someone off; to scold; to rebuke (often passive voice)\nto drill into; to train\nto narrow down (one's focus); to whittle down\nto gather up (curtain, etc.); to tighten (drawstring)\nto stop down (lens)\nto turn down (e.g. radio)\nto bend (bow); to draw\nto hold down; to constrict; to immobilize {sumo term}" },
	{ "question": "綱渡り", "answers": [ "つなわたり" ], "comment": "tightrope walking; funambulism" },
	{ "question": "網膜", "answers": [ "もうまく" ], "comment": "retina" },
	{ "question": "緊張", "answers": [ "きんちょう" ], "comment": "tension; mental strain; nervousness" },
	{ "question": "緊迫", "answers": [ "きんぱく" ], "comment": "tension; strain" },
	{ "question": "締めて", "answers": [ "しめて" ], "comment": "in all; all told" },
	{ "question": "締結", "answers": [ "ていけつ" ], "comment": "conclusion; execution (of a contract); entering (into treaty)\nfastening (as in a joint)" },
	{ "question": "緩やか", "answers": [ "ゆるやか" ], "comment": "loose; slack\ngentle; easy; slow\nlenient; liberal; lax" },
	{ "question": "緩和", "answers": [ "かんわ" ], "comment": "relief; mitigation; alleviation; relaxation; softening" },
	{ "question": "緩急", "answers": [ "かんきゅう" ], "comment": "pace; tempo; slow and fast\nin case of emergency" },
	{ "question": "縛り", "answers": [ "しばり" ], "comment": "binding\nregulation; limit" },
	{ "question": "縫い", "answers": [ "ぬい" ], "comment": "embroidery; sewing" },
	{ "question": "縫合", "answers": [ "ほうごう" ], "comment": "seam; suture; stitch" },
	{ "question": "縫製", "answers": [ "ほうせい" ], "comment": "sewing" },
	{ "question": "縮まる", "answers": [ "ちぢまる" ], "comment": "to shorten; to narrow; to close" },
	{ "question": "繁華街", "answers": [ "はんかがい" ], "comment": "business district; shopping district; bustling street; shopping centre; shopping center; downtown" },
	{ "question": "繕う", "answers": [ "つくろう" ], "comment": "to mend; to patch up; to repair; to fix; to darn; to trim\nto fix (hair, clothes, appearance etc.); to adjust; to tidy up; to groom\nto keep up appearances; to cover up (mistakes etc.); to gloss over\nto treat (illness, injury, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "群がる", "answers": [ "むらがる" ], "comment": "to swarm; to gather" },
	{ "question": "翻意", "answers": [ "ほんい" ], "comment": "changing one's mind" },
	{ "question": "翻訳", "answers": [ "ほんやく" ], "comment": "translation\nde-encryption; deciphering\nrendering" },
	{ "question": "老婆", "answers": [ "ろうば" ], "comment": "old woman" },
	{ "question": "老婆心", "answers": [ "ろうばしん" ], "comment": "concern" },
	{ "question": "耐乏", "answers": [ "たいぼう" ], "comment": "austerity; voluntary privation" },
	{ "question": "耕す", "answers": [ "たがやす" ], "comment": "to till; to plow; to plough; to cultivate" },
	{ "question": "聴衆", "answers": [ "ちょうしゅう" ], "comment": "audience; attendance; hearers" },
	{ "question": "肝心", "answers": [ "かんじん" ], "comment": "essential; fundamental; crucial; vital; main" },
	{ "question": "肝要", "answers": [ "かんよう" ], "comment": "extremely important; essential; vital; crucial" },
	{ "question": "肝試し", "answers": [ "きもだめし" ], "comment": "test of courage; dare" },
	{ "question": "胃袋", "answers": [ "いぶくろ" ], "comment": "stomach; breadbasket; inner man\ndietary needs" },
	{ "question": "背ける", "answers": [ "そむける" ], "comment": "to turn one's face away; to avert one's eyes" },
	{ "question": "胎児", "answers": [ "たいじ" ], "comment": "fetus; foetus; embryo; unborn child" },
	{ "question": "胎動", "answers": [ "たいどう" ], "comment": "quickening; foetal (fetal) movement; fomenting (trouble)" },
	{ "question": "脅す", "answers": [ "おどす" ], "comment": "to threaten; to menace; to bully" },
	{ "question": "脅威", "answers": [ "きょうい" ], "comment": "threat; menace" },
	{ "question": "脳波", "answers": [ "のうは" ], "comment": "brain waves\nelectroencephalogram; EEG" },
	{ "question": "脳裏", "answers": [ "のうり" ], "comment": "one's mind" },
	{ "question": "膨らむ", "answers": [ "ふくらむ" ], "comment": "to expand; to swell (out); to get big; to become inflated" },
	{ "question": "膨大", "answers": [ "ぼうだい" ], "comment": "huge; vast; enormous; colossal; extensive; multitudinous\nswelling; expansion" },
	{ "question": "膨張", "answers": [ "ぼうちょう" ], "comment": "expansion; swelling; increase; growth" },
	{ "question": "臨む", "answers": [ "のぞむ" ], "comment": "to look out on\nto face\nto deal with\nto attend (e.g. function); to appear (e.g. in court)" },
	{ "question": "至当", "answers": [ "しとう" ], "comment": "just; fair; proper; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "至極", "answers": [ "しごく" ], "comment": "very; extremely; exceedingly; quite; most\ntop; highest; best" },
	{ "question": "花壇", "answers": [ "かだん" ], "comment": "flower bed" },
	{ "question": "花婿", "answers": [ "はなむこ" ], "comment": "bridegroom" },
	{ "question": "花嫁", "answers": [ "はなよめ" ], "comment": "bride" },
	{ "question": "芳香", "answers": [ "ほうこう" ], "comment": "perfume; fragrance; aroma; balm; sweet scent" },
	{ "question": "苗", "answers": [ "なえ" ], "comment": "seedling\nMiao (people); Hmong" },
	{ "question": "苗床", "answers": [ "なえどこ" ], "comment": "nursery; seedbed; seed-plot" },
	{ "question": "苗木", "answers": [ "なえぎ" ], "comment": "seedling; sapling; young tree" },
	{ "question": "菊", "answers": [ "きく" ], "comment": "chrysanthemum (Chrysanthemum morifolium)" },
	{ "question": "華やか", "answers": [ "はなやか" ], "comment": "showy; brilliant; gorgeous; florid; gay" },
	{ "question": "落胆", "answers": [ "らくたん" ], "comment": "discouragement; despondency; dejection; disappointment" },
	{ "question": "葬儀", "answers": [ "そうぎ" ], "comment": "funeral service" },
	{ "question": "蒸し器", "answers": [ "むしき" ], "comment": "steamer" },
	{ "question": "薄い", "answers": [ "うすい" ], "comment": "thin\npale; light\nwatery; dilute; sparse\nweak (taste, etc.)\nslim (probability, etc.); small" },
	{ "question": "藩主", "answers": [ "はんしゅ" ], "comment": "feudal lord; daimyo" },
	{ "question": "藩校", "answers": [ "はんこう" ], "comment": "clan school; han school" },
	{ "question": "虐待", "answers": [ "ぎゃくたい" ], "comment": "abuse; ill-treatment; maltreatment; mistreatment; cruelty" },
	{ "question": "虚", "answers": [ "きょ" ], "comment": "sky; the air; the heavens\nweather\nfar-off place; distant place\nstate of mind; feeling\n(from) memory; (by) heart\nfalsehood; lie\nsomehow; vaguely\nfake\nhollow; cavity; hole\nunpreparedness\nfalsehood\nChinese \"Emptiness\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "虚勢", "answers": [ "きょせい" ], "comment": "bluff" },
	{ "question": "蛮行", "answers": [ "ばんこう" ], "comment": "act of barbarity; brutality; barbarism" },
	{ "question": "衝撃", "answers": [ "しょうげき" ], "comment": "shock; impact; crash" },
	{ "question": "衝突", "answers": [ "しょうとつ" ], "comment": "collision; crash; running into\nconflict; quarrel; clashing" },
	{ "question": "衰弱", "answers": [ "すいじゃく" ], "comment": "weakness; debility; breakdown; prostration" },
	{ "question": "衰退", "answers": [ "すいたい" ], "comment": "decline; degeneration; decay; waning; ebbing" },
	{ "question": "袋", "answers": [ "ふくろ" ], "comment": "bag; sack; pouch\nskin of an orange (and other like fruits)\ndead end\nplot of land surrounded by water\ncounter for things inside a bag" },
	{ "question": "裁量", "answers": [ "さいりょう" ], "comment": "admeasure; discretion" },
	{ "question": "裂ける", "answers": [ "さける" ], "comment": "to split; to tear; to burst" },
	{ "question": "装う", "answers": [ "よそおう" ], "comment": "to dress\nto pretend; to feign\nto serve; to dish up; to prepare" },
	{ "question": "装丁", "answers": [ "そうてい" ], "comment": "binding (book); format" },
	{ "question": "裏切る", "answers": [ "うらぎる" ], "comment": "to betray; to turn traitor to; to double-cross" },
	{ "question": "裏表", "answers": [ "うらおもて" ], "comment": "back and front; inside and outside; both sides\ninside out (e.g. clothing)\ndouble-dealing; two faces (c.f. two-faced)\noutward appearance and actual condition; inner workings" },
	{ "question": "補う", "answers": [ "おぎなう" ], "comment": "to compensate for; to supplement" },
	{ "question": "裸", "answers": [ "はだか" ], "comment": "naked; nude; bare" },
	{ "question": "裸眼", "answers": [ "らがん" ], "comment": "naked eye" },
	{ "question": "要因", "answers": [ "よういん" ], "comment": "main cause; primary factor" },
	{ "question": "覆う", "answers": [ "おおう" ], "comment": "to cover; to hide; to conceal; to wrap; to disguise" },
	{ "question": "覆す", "answers": [ "くつがえす" ], "comment": "to overturn; to capsize; to upset\nto overthrow (government etc.)\nto reverse (decision etc.); to disprove (an established theory etc.); to overrule" },
	{ "question": "覆水", "answers": [ "ふくすい" ], "comment": "spilt water" },
	{ "question": "覆面", "answers": [ "ふくめん" ], "comment": "mask; veil; disguise\nanonymous; unmarked; incognito" },
	{ "question": "覚ます", "answers": [ "さます" ], "comment": "to awaken\nto disabuse\nto sober up" },
	{ "question": "覚悟", "answers": [ "かくご" ], "comment": "resolution; resignation; readiness; preparedness" },
	{ "question": "観覧", "answers": [ "かんらん" ], "comment": "viewing" },
	{ "question": "角膜", "answers": [ "かくまく" ], "comment": "cornea" },
	{ "question": "解凍", "answers": [ "かいとう" ], "comment": "thaw; defrosting\ndecompression (e.g. of a file); unpacking; extracting; unzipping" },
	{ "question": "訂正", "answers": [ "ていせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; amendment" },
	{ "question": "記念碑", "answers": [ "きねんひ" ], "comment": "commemorative plaque (usu. on a stone); stone monument (bearing an inscription)" },
	{ "question": "訪ねる", "answers": [ "たずねる" ], "comment": "to visit; to call on; to pay a visit to" },
	{ "question": "訪欧", "answers": [ "ほうおう" ], "comment": "visit to Europe" },
	{ "question": "設ける", "answers": [ "もうける" ], "comment": "to prepare ahead of time\nto create; to establish" },
	{ "question": "設立", "answers": [ "せつりつ" ], "comment": "establishment; founding; incorporation (of a business)" },
	{ "question": "許容", "answers": [ "きょよう" ], "comment": "permission; pardon" },
	{ "question": "訳", "answers": [ "わけ" ], "comment": "conclusion from reasoning, judgement or calculation based on something read or heard; reason; cause; meaning; circumstances; situation\ntranslation; version (e.g. \"English version\")" },
	{ "question": "詠ずる", "answers": [ "えいずる" ], "comment": "to compose (e.g. poem)\nto recite; to intone; to chant" },
	{ "question": "試し", "answers": [ "ためし" ], "comment": "trial; test" },
	{ "question": "該博", "answers": [ "がいはく" ], "comment": "profundity; extensive (knowledge)" },
	{ "question": "該当", "answers": [ "がいとう" ], "comment": "corresponding to; being applicable to; relevant to; coming under; falling under; applying to; fulfilling; qualifying as" },
	{ "question": "誉れ", "answers": [ "ほまれ" ], "comment": "honour; honor" },
	{ "question": "認める", "answers": [ "みとめる" ], "comment": "to write up\nto recognize; to recognise; to observe; to notice\nto deem; to judge; to assess\nto approve; to deem acceptable; to allow\nto admit; to accept; to confess (to a charge)\nto watch steadily; to observe carefully\nto renown; to give renown to; to appreciate; to acknowledge" },
	{ "question": "認定", "answers": [ "にんてい" ], "comment": "authorization; authorisation; acknowledgment; acknowledgement; certification; recognition" },
	{ "question": "誘う", "answers": [ "さそう", "いざなう" ], "comment": "to invite; to ask; to call (for)\nto tempt; to lure; to induce" },
	{ "question": "誘導", "answers": [ "ゆうどう" ], "comment": "guidance; leading; induction; introduction; incitement; inducement" },
	{ "question": "誘致", "answers": [ "ゆうち" ], "comment": "attraction; lure; invitation" },
	{ "question": "誤る", "answers": [ "あやまる" ], "comment": "to make a mistake; to err\nto mislead; to misguide" },
	{ "question": "請願", "answers": [ "せいがん" ], "comment": "petition" },
	{ "question": "諮る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to consult with; to discuss; to confer; to deliberate" },
	{ "question": "諮問", "answers": [ "しもん" ], "comment": "consultation; question; enquiry; inquiry" },
	{ "question": "警鐘", "answers": [ "けいしょう" ], "comment": "alarm bell; fire bell\nwarning; wake-up call" },
	{ "question": "譲る", "answers": [ "ゆずる" ], "comment": "to turn over; to assign; to hand over; to transmit; to convey; to sell; to dispose of\nto yield; to surrender; to concede" },
	{ "question": "譲歩", "answers": [ "じょうほ" ], "comment": "concession; conciliation; compromise" },
	{ "question": "豊か", "answers": [ "ゆたか" ], "comment": "abundant; wealthy; plentiful; rich; affluent\nvery; extremely; full of; great" },
	{ "question": "豊潤", "answers": [ "ほうじゅん" ], "comment": "rich and prosperous; luxurious; abundant" },
	{ "question": "豚肉", "answers": [ "ぶたにく" ], "comment": "pork" },
	{ "question": "豪華", "answers": [ "ごうか" ], "comment": "wonderful; gorgeous; splendor; splendour; pomp; extravagance" },
	{ "question": "負債", "answers": [ "ふさい" ], "comment": "debt; liabilities" },
	{ "question": "財布", "answers": [ "さいふ" ], "comment": "purse; handbag; wallet" },
	{ "question": "貧乏", "answers": [ "びんぼう" ], "comment": "poverty; destitute; poor" },
	{ "question": "貫く", "answers": [ "つらぬく" ], "comment": "to go through; to pierce; to penetrate\nto carry out; to persist; to keep (faith); to stick to (principles); to maintain (independence)" },
	{ "question": "貫通", "answers": [ "かんつう" ], "comment": "piercing; penetrating; perforating; passing through\nbeing well versed (in something)" },
	{ "question": "貴族", "answers": [ "きぞく" ], "comment": "noble; aristocrat" },
	{ "question": "費やす", "answers": [ "ついやす" ], "comment": "to spend; to expend; to consume\nto waste; to squander; to throw away\nto devote" },
	{ "question": "貿易", "answers": [ "ぼうえき" ], "comment": "trade (foreign)" },
	{ "question": "賢い", "answers": [ "かしこい" ], "comment": "wise; clever; smart" },
	{ "question": "賢明", "answers": [ "けんめい" ], "comment": "wisdom; intelligence; prudence" },
	{ "question": "赤裸々", "answers": [ "せきらら" ], "comment": "nakedness; nudity\nfrankness" },
	{ "question": "赴く", "answers": [ "おもむく" ], "comment": "to go in the direction of; to proceed toward; to proceed according to; to repair to; to betake oneself to\nto become; to face (facts, circumstances, etc.)\nto abide by; to agree to; to consent to; to obey" },
	{ "question": "赴任", "answers": [ "ふにん" ], "comment": "moving to a different location to start a new job; (proceeding to) new appointment" },
	{ "question": "超人", "answers": [ "ちょうじん" ], "comment": "superman; superwoman\nUbermensch (e.g. Nietzsche's ideal man of the future); overman" },
	{ "question": "超越", "answers": [ "ちょうえつ" ], "comment": "transcendence; transcendency\ntranscendental\nto transcend; to rise above" },
	{ "question": "足袋", "answers": [ "たび" ], "comment": "tabi; Japanese socks (with split toe)" },
	{ "question": "軌跡", "answers": [ "きせき" ], "comment": "tire track\ntraces of a person or thing; path one has taken\nlocus" },
	{ "question": "軌道", "answers": [ "きどう" ], "comment": "orbit; trajectory\nrailroad track\n(on the right) track; going smoothly" },
	{ "question": "転覆", "answers": [ "てんぷく" ], "comment": "capsizing; overturn; turning over; upset\noverthrow (e.g. a government)" },
	{ "question": "軽さ", "answers": [ "かるさ" ], "comment": "lightness" },
	{ "question": "輪郭", "answers": [ "りんかく" ], "comment": "contour; outline; border; silhouette\nsummary; outline; sketch\nlooks; features; appearance" },
	{ "question": "辛勝", "answers": [ "しんしょう" ], "comment": "narrow victory" },
	{ "question": "辛抱", "answers": [ "しんぼう" ], "comment": "patience; endurance" },
	{ "question": "辱知", "answers": [ "じょくち" ], "comment": "acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "近郊", "answers": [ "きんこう" ], "comment": "suburbs; outskirts" },
	{ "question": "追随", "answers": [ "ついずい" ], "comment": "following (in the footsteps of)\ncatching up with; coming level with" },
	{ "question": "退く", "answers": [ "しりぞく" ], "comment": "to step aside; to move (i.e. out of the way); to make way\nto resign; to retire; to quit; to secede\nto step back; to move back; to retreat\nto withdraw (from the presence of a superior); to leave; to exit\nto resign; to retire; to quit\nto concede\nto move back; to draw back; to recede\nto lessen; to subside; to ebb\nto resign; to retire; to quit" },
	{ "question": "逆らう", "answers": [ "さからう" ], "comment": "to go against; to oppose; to disobey; to defy" },
	{ "question": "通気孔", "answers": [ "つうきこう" ], "comment": "vent" },
	{ "question": "連携", "answers": [ "れんけい" ], "comment": "cooperation; coordination; link" },
	{ "question": "逮捕", "answers": [ "たいほ" ], "comment": "arrest; apprehension; capture" },
	{ "question": "遂げる", "answers": [ "とげる" ], "comment": "to accomplish; to achieve; to carry out\nto arrive at (a certain outcome); to come to; to end with" },
	{ "question": "遂行", "answers": [ "すいこう" ], "comment": "accomplishment; execution" },
	{ "question": "過程", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "process; course; mechanism" },
	{ "question": "遭遇", "answers": [ "そうぐう" ], "comment": "encounter; being confronted with (e.g. difficulty); meeting with (e.g. accident)" },
	{ "question": "遭難", "answers": [ "そうなん" ], "comment": "disaster; shipwreck; accident; being stranded" },
	{ "question": "遵守", "answers": [ "じゅんしゅ" ], "comment": "compliance; adherence (to a set of rules); (religious) observance" },
	{ "question": "選択", "answers": [ "せんたく" ], "comment": "selection; choice; option" },
	{ "question": "邦人", "answers": [ "ほうじん" ], "comment": "Japanese national (esp. one living overseas)\nfellow countryman" },
	{ "question": "邦画", "answers": [ "ほうが" ], "comment": "Japanese film\nJapanese painting" },
	{ "question": "邪念", "answers": [ "じゃねん" ], "comment": "wicked thought; wicked mind" },
	{ "question": "邪推", "answers": [ "じゃすい" ], "comment": "distrust; unjust suspicion" },
	{ "question": "邪道", "answers": [ "じゃどう" ], "comment": "evil course; heresy" },
	{ "question": "邪魔", "answers": [ "じゃま" ], "comment": "hindrance; obstacle; nuisance\nto visit (somebody's home)\ndemon who hinders Buddhist training; demon who obstructs sentient beings from maintaining moral behaviour" },
	{ "question": "郊外", "answers": [ "こうがい" ], "comment": "suburb; outskirts" },
	{ "question": "酔う", "answers": [ "よう" ], "comment": "to get drunk; to become intoxicated\nto feel sick (e.g. in a vehicle); to become nauseated\nto be elated; to be exalted; to be spellbound; to be in raptures" },
	{ "question": "酵素", "answers": [ "こうそ" ], "comment": "enzyme" },
	{ "question": "重鎮", "answers": [ "じゅうちん" ], "comment": "leader; authority; mainstay" },
	{ "question": "野蛮", "answers": [ "やばん" ], "comment": "savage; uncivilized; uncivilised; barbarian" },
	{ "question": "金塊", "answers": [ "きんかい" ], "comment": "gold nugget; gold bullion; gold bar; gold ingot" },
	{ "question": "鋳る", "answers": [ "いる" ], "comment": "to cast; to mint; to coin" },
	{ "question": "鋳造", "answers": [ "ちゅうぞう" ], "comment": "casting; founding; minting" },
	{ "question": "錠剤", "answers": [ "じょうざい" ], "comment": "pill; lozenge; tablet" },
	{ "question": "錯乱", "answers": [ "さくらん" ], "comment": "confusion; distraction; derangement" },
	{ "question": "錯覚", "answers": [ "さっかく" ], "comment": "optical illusion; hallucination\nmisapprehension; delusion" },
	{ "question": "鍛える", "answers": [ "きたえる" ], "comment": "to forge; to temper\nto drill; to train; to discipline" },
	{ "question": "鍛錬", "answers": [ "たんれん" ], "comment": "tempering (metal); annealing; forging\ntoughening; disciplining; training" },
	{ "question": "鎮痛剤", "answers": [ "ちんつうざい" ], "comment": "analgesic; painkiller; sedative; tranquilizer; tranquiliser" },
	{ "question": "鐘", "answers": [ "かね" ], "comment": "bell (often a large hanging bell); chime" },
	{ "question": "鐘楼", "answers": [ "しょうろう" ], "comment": "belfry; bell tower" },
	{ "question": "長寿", "answers": [ "ちょうじゅ" ], "comment": "longevity" },
	{ "question": "開催", "answers": [ "かいさい" ], "comment": "holding a meeting; opening an exhibition; hosting (e.g. the Olympics)" },
	{ "question": "開墾", "answers": [ "かいこん" ], "comment": "cultivating new land; clearing; reclamation" },
	{ "question": "間隔", "answers": [ "かんかく" ], "comment": "space; interval; SPC" },
	{ "question": "閲覧", "answers": [ "えつらん" ], "comment": "inspection; reading\nbrowsing (the WWW, Internet); web browsing" },
	{ "question": "闘魂", "answers": [ "とうこん" ], "comment": "fighting spirit" },
	{ "question": "闘鶏", "answers": [ "とうけい" ], "comment": "cockfight; fighting cock" },
	{ "question": "阻害", "answers": [ "そがい" ], "comment": "obstruction; inhibition" },
	{ "question": "限る", "answers": [ "かぎる" ], "comment": "to restrict; to limit; to confine\nto be restricted to; to be limited to; to be confined to" },
	{ "question": "除く", "answers": [ "のぞく" ], "comment": "to remove; to eliminate; to eradicate\nto exclude; to except" },
	{ "question": "除籍", "answers": [ "じょせき" ], "comment": "removing a name\nexpelling (e.g. from school); decommissioning" },
	{ "question": "陪審", "answers": [ "ばいしん" ], "comment": "jury" },
	{ "question": "陰謀", "answers": [ "いんぼう" ], "comment": "plot; intrigue; scheme\nconspiracy; agreement between two or more people to commit an unlawful act" },
	{ "question": "陳腐", "answers": [ "ちんぷ" ], "comment": "stale; hackneyed; cliched" },
	{ "question": "陳謝", "answers": [ "ちんしゃ" ], "comment": "apology" },
	{ "question": "陵墓", "answers": [ "りょうぼ" ], "comment": "imperial tomb; imperial mausoleum" },
	{ "question": "陶芸", "answers": [ "とうげい" ], "comment": "ceramic art; ceramics" },
	{ "question": "陶酔", "answers": [ "とうすい" ], "comment": "intoxication" },
	{ "question": "険しい", "answers": [ "けわしい" ], "comment": "precipitous; rugged; inaccessible; impregnable; steep\ngrim; severe; stern" },
	{ "question": "険阻", "answers": [ "けんそ" ], "comment": "precipice; steep (e.g. mountain pass)" },
	{ "question": "隆盛", "answers": [ "りゅうせい" ], "comment": "prosperity; flourishing; thriving" },
	{ "question": "隆起", "answers": [ "りゅうき" ], "comment": "protuberance; bulge; protrusion; projection; swell\nrise; uplift; upheaval; elevation" },
	{ "question": "随意", "answers": [ "ずいい" ], "comment": "voluntary; optional; free; elective" },
	{ "question": "随時", "answers": [ "ずいじ" ], "comment": "as needed; as occasion demands\nat any time" },
	{ "question": "隔たり", "answers": [ "へだたり" ], "comment": "distance; interval; gap; difference; estrangement" },
	{ "question": "隔てる", "answers": [ "へだてる" ], "comment": "to separate (by distance, time, etc.); to isolate; to partition; to divide\nto interpose; to have between\nto alienate; to estrange" },
	{ "question": "隔絶", "answers": [ "かくぜつ" ], "comment": "isolation; separation; remoteness; seclusion; reclusion; inaccessibility; sequestration" },
	{ "question": "際限", "answers": [ "さいげん" ], "comment": "limits; end; bounds" },
	{ "question": "隠匿", "answers": [ "いんとく" ], "comment": "concealment" },
	{ "question": "隻眼", "answers": [ "せきがん" ], "comment": "eye (for pictures, etc.); one eye" },
	{ "question": "雇う", "answers": [ "やとう" ], "comment": "to employ\nto hire; to charter" },
	{ "question": "雇用", "answers": [ "こよう" ], "comment": "employment (long term); hire" },
	{ "question": "雑炊", "answers": [ "ぞうすい" ], "comment": "rice gruel containing vegetables, fish, etc., and seasoned with miso or soy sauce" },
	{ "question": "雑誌", "answers": [ "ざっし" ], "comment": "journal; magazine; periodical" },
	{ "question": "難しい", "answers": [ "むずかしい" ], "comment": "difficult; hard; troublesome; complicated; serious (disease, problem, etc.)\nfussy; particular; fastidious; hard to please; displeased\ngloomy; glum; sullen; serious (look)\ndirty; unclean; filthy; detestable\nunpleasant; uncomfortable; creepy; spooky" },
	{ "question": "難癖", "answers": [ "なんくせ" ], "comment": "fault" },
	{ "question": "雪崩", "answers": [ "なだれ" ], "comment": "avalanche; snowslide" },
	{ "question": "雪辱", "answers": [ "せつじょく" ], "comment": "vindication of honour; vindication of honor; making up for loss; revenge" },
	{ "question": "零度", "answers": [ "れいど" ], "comment": "zero; absolute zero (temp.); freezing point" },
	{ "question": "零細", "answers": [ "れいさい" ], "comment": "insignificant; trifling; paltry; cottage (industry); tiny (company)" },
	{ "question": "零落", "answers": [ "れいらく" ], "comment": "falling into straitened circumstances; downfall; ruin" },
	{ "question": "霊峰", "answers": [ "れいほう" ], "comment": "sacred mountain" },
	{ "question": "預ける", "answers": [ "あずける" ], "comment": "to give into custody; to leave (a child) in the care of; to entrust; to deposit\nto lean on; to put one's weight on" },
	{ "question": "顧みる", "answers": [ "かえりみる" ], "comment": "to look back (e.g. over shoulder or at the past); to turn around\nto reflect on the past; to reconsider; to review\nto reflect on oneself; to introspect; to contemplate oneself\nto consider (usu. used in negative); to concern oneself about; to pay attention to; to take into consideration" },
	{ "question": "顧問", "answers": [ "こもん" ], "comment": "adviser; advisor; consultant" },
	{ "question": "飛ばす", "answers": [ "とばす" ], "comment": "to fly; to fire; to hurl; to launch; to make fly\nto skip over; to omit; to drop (e.g. stitch)\nto run or drive fast; to gallop\nto spread a rumour (rumor); to tell a story; to tell a joke\nto remove; to get rid of; to transfer\nto attack; to jeer at" },
	{ "question": "食糧", "answers": [ "しょくりょう" ], "comment": "food (esp. staple food such as rice or wheat); provisions; rations; food supply" },
	{ "question": "飽き", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "weariness; tiresomeness" },
	{ "question": "飽和", "answers": [ "ほうわ" ], "comment": "saturation" },
	{ "question": "飽食", "answers": [ "ほうしょく" ], "comment": "gluttony; satiation; engorgement" },
	{ "question": "養う", "answers": [ "やしなう" ], "comment": "to support; to maintain; to provide for\nto bring up; to raise; to rear; to feed\nto adopt (a child)\nto cultivate (a habit, a quality, etc.); to develop; to build up; to foster\nto recuperate (from injury, illness, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "養豚", "answers": [ "ようとん" ], "comment": "pig-keeping; pig farming" },
	{ "question": "餓死", "answers": [ "がし" ], "comment": "(death from) starvation; starving to death" },
	{ "question": "餓鬼", "answers": [ "がき" ], "comment": "brat; kids; urchin; little devil\npreta; hungry ghost; ghoul" },
	{ "question": "駐車", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "parking (e.g. car)" },
	{ "question": "騎手", "answers": [ "きしゅ" ], "comment": "horseman; rider" },
	{ "question": "驚く", "answers": [ "おどろく" ], "comment": "to be surprised; to be astonished" },
	{ "question": "骨髄", "answers": [ "こつずい" ], "comment": "bone marrow; medulla\ntrue spirit; one's mind" },
	{ "question": "魅了", "answers": [ "みりょう" ], "comment": "fascination\nto charm; to fascinate; to mesmerize" },
	{ "question": "魅力", "answers": [ "みりょく" ], "comment": "charm; fascination; glamour; glamor; attraction; appeal" },
	{ "question": "魅惑", "answers": [ "みわく" ], "comment": "attraction; fascination; lure; captivation; charm" },
	{ "question": "魔法", "answers": [ "まほう" ], "comment": "magic; witchcraft; sorcery" },
	{ "question": "鯨", "answers": [ "くじら" ], "comment": "whale (Cetacea spp.)" },
	{ "question": "鶏", "answers": [ "にわとり" ], "comment": "(domestic) chicken\nchicken (meat)" },
	{ "question": "鼻孔", "answers": [ "びこう" ], "comment": "nostril; nostrils; naris; nares" }
]
}
